aboard.
乗ってます。
Welcome to the Institute of Science and Technology of the Central Institute of Science and Technology.
中央科学技術研究所科学技術研究所へようこそ。
I am the director of the Institute of Science and Technology of the Central Institute of Science and Technology.
私は中央科学技術研究所科学技術研究所長を務めております。
I am honored to be able to introduce today's host.
本日のホストをご紹介できることを光栄に思います。
Vice President Wang Jingxing of our Central Plains Institute
中原研究所副所長 王 京興
here?
ここ？
because our guest
なぜなら私たちのゲストだから
He is our new Secretary-General of the Central Plains Academy
彼はセントラル・プレーンズ・アカデミーの新しい事務総長です
Secretary Peng Jinkun Peng
彭ジンクン・ペン事務総長
OK, then I'll hand the mic over to today's host.
はい、それではマイクを今日の司会者に渡します。
this
これ
thanks for this our host
私たちのホストに感謝します
Director Chen
チェン監督
Thank you all so much for taking the time out of your busy schedule to listen to this
皆様、お忙しい中、貴重なお時間を割いて聞いていただきまして、誠にありがとうございました
Share this Feast of Wisdom
この知恵の饗宴を共有する
That
それか
Logically, I just want to introduce
論理的に、私はただ紹介したいだけです
this our keynote speaker
これが私たちの基調講演者です
what about the fact
事実はどうですか
our keynote speaker
私たちの基調講演者
For the people of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学関係者へ
no stranger
見知らぬ人ではありません
In fact, he has been
実際、彼はこれまでに
Our National Taiwan University
私たちの国立台湾大学
Serve hard
一生懸命奉仕する
Poached by Central Researcher
中央研究員による密猟
is now the director of our Central Fellows Institute of Law
現在はセントラルフェローズ法律研究所の所長です
he was also a justice
彼は正義の人でもあった
So everyone is familiar with his name
だから誰もが彼の名前を知っています
Sometimes I have seen his name in the media magazines before
以前メディア雑誌で時々彼の名前を見たことがある
listened to his advice
彼のアドバイスを聞いた
then i am
それなら私は
Actually, he's an old friend to me personally.
実際、彼は私にとって個人的に古い友人です。
Because he went to Harvard University in the United States for a year
アメリカのハーバード大学に1年間通っていたので、
this for research
これは研究用です
we just met there
私たちはそこで会ったばかりです
Then I still wish to compare some of his
それから私はまだ彼のいくつかを比較したいと思っています
objective study
客観的な研究
After sharing this report with everyone
このレポートをみんなで共有したら
Of course he didn't have to say he was
もちろん、彼はそうであると言う必要はありませんでした
Graduated from the Law Department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学法学部卒業
That also went to graduate school
それも大学院に行った
Then he later in the United States
その後、彼はその後アメリカで
Connors University
コナーズ大学
Cornell University's Juris Doctor
コーネル大学法学博士
that he
彼が
It is now our Academia Sinica's Institute of Law
現在は中央研究院の法学研究所となっています。
Distinguished Researcher and Director
特別研究員兼所長
So a Distinguished Researcher is equivalent to a University Chair Professor
したがって、特別研究員は大学の教授に相当します。
But he is also from the law school of our National Taiwan University.
しかし、彼は私たちの国立台湾大学の法科大学院の出身でもあります。
part-time professor
兼任教授
his long-standing commitment to the constitution
彼の憲法に対する長年の取り組み
Freedom of Speech Privacy
言論の自由 プライバシー
Research in the Field of Information Law
情報法分野の研究
Then this is like what I just said
それから、これは私が今言ったことと同じです
He stayed in Taiwan University for a long time
彼は台湾大学に長期滞在しました
He was from 1978 to 2003
彼は1978年から2003年までいた
He served as a teaching assistant in the law department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学法学部でティーチングアシスタントを務めた
Lecturer Associate Professor Professor
講師 副教授 教授
2003 to 2011
2003年から2011年
chief justice of the judiciary
司法長官
Well, this is generally what legal people envy the most in the future is to become a university student.
まあ、これは大体、法律関係者が将来一番うらやむのは大学生になることなんです。
The judge did this, and he did it.
それが裁判官のしたことだ。
Then he will talk about one today
それから彼は今日一つについて話します
very important topic
非常に重要なトピック
There are some special revelations for our reality
私たちの現実に対する特別な啓示がいくつかあります
privacy in the information society
情報化社会におけるプライバシー
privacy
プライバシー
i remember i was in the 1980s
1980年代にいたことを覚えています
While studying at Harvard
ハーバード大学在学中
There is a very famous professor at Harvard University
ハーバード大学にとても有名な教授がいます
Called Daniel Bale
ダニエル・ベイルと呼ばれる
He learns a famous book
彼は有名な本を学びます
就是The Coming of the Poster Industrial Society
即ちポスター産業社会の到来
With the advent of the post-industrial society
脱工業化社会の到来に関しては
Then think about thirty years ago
それから30年前のことを考えてみましょう
That computer is definitely something only the rich can afford.
そのコンピューターは間違いなく金持ちだけが買えるものです。
They're all big, big computers.
それらはすべて大きなコンピューターです。
But then you have to think about saying
しかし、その後、次のように言うことを考えなければなりません
invention of computer
コンピューターの発明
will change the future of mankind
人類の未来を変えるだろう
Organization Structure Even Behavior
組織構造も行動も
But from thirty years later you see
しかし、30年後から見ると、
Sure enough, you see that this has changed so much
案の定、かなり変わったことがわかりますね
like us now
今の私たちのように
It's hard for someone like me to understand
私のような者には理解するのが難しいです
This world has become very strange to me
この世界は私にとってとても奇妙になりました
But we have this speech by Director Lin
しかし、リン監督のこのスピーチがあります。
we may know better
私たちはもっとよく知っているかもしれません
Especially when it comes to privacy, privacy, these things.
特に彼がプライバシー、プライバシーなどに関与している場合はそうです。
I think everyone is very interested
皆さんとても興味があると思います
then i won't talk nonsense
それならナンセンスなことは話さないよ
We now invite Director Lin to welcome Director Lin
それでは、林所長をお迎えいたします。
Thanks
ありがとう
Director Chen and thank you for Huang Feiyuan's introduction just now
チェン監督、黄飛源さんの紹介ありがとうございます
Thank you ladies and gentlemen too
紳士淑女の皆様もありがとうございました
Participate in today's this I want to report to you
今日はこれに参加してご報告したいと思います
theme
主題
actually, I
実は、私
Let's look at these two pictures first
まずはこの2枚の写真を見てみましょう
I actually probably won’t use this slide too much today
実は今日はこのスライドをあまり使わないかもしれません
Probably the time when the powerpoint was used
おそらくパワーポイントが使われていた時代だと思います。
mainly possible
主に可能
no way to speak or say
話すことも言うこともできない
or
また
Because some sharp legal texts will be used in it
鋭い法律文書がいくつか使用されるため、
Even if
もしそれでも
It is not easy for everyone to understand what I say in this way
私のこのように言うことを誰もが理解するのは簡単ではありません
So it would be possible to use this
したがって、これを使用することは可能です
Orpoin, other than that, I'd probably
オルポイン、それ以外ならおそらく
I really hope that I can talk to you in a relatively simple way.
比較的分かりやすくお話しできればと思っております。
let's talk
話しましょう
What I am going to talk to you about today in the information society
今日お話しする情報社会のこと
Privacy and Privacy
プライバシーとプライバシー
Let's take a look at these two pictures first
まずはこの2枚の写真を見てみましょう
here is the first
ここが最初です
sorry
ごめん
this is the second
これは2番目です
Let's take a closer look at these two
この2つを詳しく見てみましょう
I ask everyone to take a look and try this place
皆さんもぜひこの場所を見て試してみてください
If you look at this picture, this place
この写真を見ると、この場所です
It's just that if only this room looks like it has only one door
扉が一つしかないように見えるのはこの部屋だけ
For the other rooms, he is the same
他の部屋でも彼は同じです
look at another one
別のものを見てください
Take a closer look at this one
これをもっと詳しく見てください
every room here every room here
各部屋からの言葉
If he has at least a few rooms, there's only one door.
少なくともいくつかの部屋がある場合、ドアは 1 つだけです。
What I want to tell you is that this is what if
私が言いたいのは、もしこうなったら、ということです
This is a traditional building in Taiwan
これは台湾の伝統的な建物です
What about these two architectural drawings?
この 2 つの建築図面はどうでしょうか?
For these two architectural drawings, he
これら 2 つの建築図面について、彼は、
Basically after the middle of the 19th century
基本的には19世紀半ば以降
A design that is probably quite common in Taiwan
台湾ではよくあるデザインかもしれません
If such a design is generally speaking
一般的にこのようなデザインであれば、
words probably
おそらく言葉
I don't know why they designed it that way
なぜそのように設計したのか分かりません
but
しかし
If I read more articles, it might be inside
もっと記事を読めば中に入るかもしれない
and
と
Southern Fujian has something to do with Ke’s buildings
福建省南部は柯氏の建物と関係がある
For example, what we just talked about is this
たとえば、今話したのはこれです
a building
一個建設
In terms of architectural drawings, it may have something to do with Hakka
建築図面の点では客家と関係があるかもしれない
It was more like
それはもっと似ていました
In this picture, he may be with
この写真では、彼は一緒にいるかもしれません
The architectural map of southern Fujian may have something to do with it
福建省南部の建築地図はそれと関係があるかもしれない
But I was just saying maybe I
でも私はただ、もしかしたら私はそうかもしれないと言っただけです
My analysis is probably wrong
私の分析はおそらく間違っています
My analysis may be wrong, just because
私の分析は間違っている可能性があります。
I because in order to talk about what is privacy
プライバシーとは何かについて話すために
so i brought a tinted glasses
だから私は色付きのメガネを持ってきました
Look at these two pictures with prejudice
この2枚の写真を先入観を持って見てください
Then when I look at these two pictures, I feel a little happy
この２枚の写真を見ると、ちょっと幸せな気分になります
Say look we can tell you a little bit
ほら見て、少しお話しましょう
Why? Because here we can see
なぜでしょうか? ここでわかるからです
In terms of the design of these two pictures, at least as living in this
この2枚の絵のデザインは、少なくともこの世界に生きているものとして、
People who live inside may feel differently
中に住んでいる人は感じ方が違うかもしれない
If a room then this room
部屋ならこの部屋
There are many places to go in and out
出入りする場所がたくさんあります
Not only like our current society
私たちの現在の社会だけでなく
In most homes, if it is your own room
ほとんどの家庭では、自分の部屋であれば、
my room with my spouse
配偶者と私の部屋
If you are not married today
もしあなたが今日結婚していないなら
not yet married
まだ結婚していない
I live with my parents
私は両親と同居しています
children or children
子供か子供か
I also hope that everyone wants to have a separate room for themselves
また、誰もが自分専用の部屋を持ちたいと思っていることを願っています
what do you mean by separate room
別室とはどういう意味ですか
A separate room is just one door
ドアひとつで別室に
And what about this door?
で、このドアはどうでしょうか？
i can control
私はコントロールできます
should i invite people in
人を招待したほうがいいでしょうか
But you can imagine
しかし、あなたは想像することができます
If you live in one room
ワンルームに住んでいる場合
many doors
たくさんのドア
what if i live in it
そこに住んでいたらどうなるか
live in a place where i can control the door
私がドアを制御できる場所に住んでいます
It's different in this case
この場合は違います
but i just said
でも私は今言いました
i could be wrong
私は間違っているかもしれない
I may be reading it wrong
読み間違えてるかも知れません
The reason my interpretation might be wrong is because
私の解釈が間違っている可能性がある理由は、
I look at something like this with colored eyes
こんなものを色のついた目で見るんだ
But suppose I'm wrong
でも、私が間違っていると仮定してください
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
Actually, I want to tell you this from the very beginning.
実はこれを最初から言いたいのです。
like this
このような
if
もしも
if we think
私たちが考えれば
What about his privacy?
彼のプライバシーについてはどうですか？
we will proceed
進めていきます
Basic understanding, what about privacy?
基本的な理解、プライバシーについてはどうですか?
Is a minimum if in terms of space design
空間デザインの観点から言えば最小限です
If there should be a space that I can control
私がコントロールできる空間があるなら
What do these two pictures represent?
この 2 つの絵は何を表していますか?
maybe not the same
たぶん同じではない
But I also have to tell you
でも、あなたにも言わなければなりません
it doesn't mean to say
言う意味ではありません
designed like this
このように設計された
It has no concept of privacy
プライバシーの概念がない
maybe it's just something
たぶんそれはただの何かです
we all have because my thoughts are
私たち全員が持っている、なぜなら私の考えは
based on each society
それぞれの社会に基づいて
Every society has a concept of privacy
どの社会にもプライバシーの概念があります
that's just saying
それはただ言っているだけです
What about in a different society or in the same society?
違う社会や同じ社会ではどうなるでしょうか？
In different times
さまざまな時代に
content that may be private
プライベートである可能性のあるコンテンツ
may not be the same
同じではないかもしれない
That's why we said, in fact, everyone, I just talked about it at the beginning
だから私たちはこう言いました、実は皆さん、私は最初にそれについて話したばかりです
Design drawings of the two rooms
2つの部屋の設計図
In fact, it was probably after the middle of the 19th century.
実際、それはおそらく 19 世紀半ば以降でした。
The general architecture in Taiwan looks like this
台湾の一般的な建築はこんな感じ
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
means that at the same time we exist
それは同時に私たちが存在していることを意味します
This kind of house with two designs
2つのデザインがあるこんな家
that doesn't mean
それは意味がありません
Only their words have privacy
彼らの言葉だけがプライバシーを持っています
there is no privacy
プライバシーはありません
not like this
こんなんじゃない
but what
でも何
maybe they are different
もしかしたら違うかもしれない
For private content
プライベートなコンテンツの場合
may think differently
違う考えかもしれない
Guys, think again
皆さん、もう一度考えてください
That just talked to the vice president
それはちょうど副社長と話したところです
just chatting
ただおしゃべりしてるだけ
We had a conversation with the vice president this year
今年も副社長と対談しました
go to italy
イタリアに行く
When we got to Italy we went to Florins
イタリアに着いたとき、私たちはフロリンズに行きました
The one from Florins
フロリンのもの
what i forgot was that it belonged to the lord
私が忘れていたのはそれが主のものだったということ
He later became a museum
彼は後に博物館になりました
if we go to that museum
もし私たちがその美術館に行ったら
you can see that museum
あなたはその博物館を見ることができます
Then just keep thinking about that space
そしてその空間について考え続けてください
He is from this room to another room
彼はこの部屋から別の部屋にいます
can pass
通過できる
Think about it again everyone
皆さんもう一度考えてみてください
been to france
フランスに行った
Germany, Austria
ドイツ、オーストリア
What about these European countries?
これらのヨーロッパ諸国はどうでしょうか？
If we go to that kind of palace
そんな宮殿に行ったら
or the lord kind
または主の種類
When visiting the building
建物を訪れる際には
He is now open
彼は今オープンしました
sometimes it has become a museum
時には博物館になることもあります
Let's think about the space design
空間デザインを考えてみましょう
I don't know about the space design
空間デザインは分からない
Just right for our visit now, right?
今の訪問にちょうどいいですよね？
from this room to another room
この部屋から別の部屋へ
No need to go out again to the hallway
もう一度廊下に出る必要はありません
then walk down the corridor
それから廊下を歩きます
use a room
部屋を使う
No, but every room is accessible
いいえ、ただしどの部屋もアクセス可能です
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
So this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いですね
at the same time
在同時間
that may have been at that time
それはその時だったかもしれない
maybe in continental europe
たぶん大陸ヨーロッパでは
their words at the same time
彼らの言葉は同時に
It may be for the nobles or the royal family
貴族や王族向けかもしれません
I think they are very modern
とても現代的だと思います
A design of Fashion
ファッションのデザイン
they don't necessarily think
彼らは必ずしも考えていない
they may not think that means
彼らはそれが意味するとは思っていないかもしれない
I must have a separate room for each
それぞれに別々の部屋が必要です
It means privacy
それはプライバシーを意味します
probably not the idea
おそらくその考えはありません
so i just said
だから私はちょうど言った
I'm from a biased perspective
私は偏った見方をしています
look at something like this
このようなものを見てください
this kind of thing
このようなこと
I also wanted to tell you
私も伝えたかった
Don't just say that
そんなことばかり言わないで
they have no privacy
彼らにはプライバシーがありません
not privacy
プライバシーではない
Just look at it with a hard eye
ただ厳しい目で見てください
maybe they are in this place
もしかしたら彼らはこの場所にいるかもしれない
maybe from my point of view
おそらく私の観点からすると
They didn't protect the privacy of the person who lived in the room
その部屋に住んでいる人のプライバシーが守られなかった
But maybe he has more privacy elsewhere than we do.
しかし、おそらく彼は私たちよりも他の場所でより多くのプライバシーを持っています。
so what
だから何
What about in different societies?
異なる社会ではどうなるでしょうか？
Although every society has its own concept of privacy
どの社会にも独自のプライバシーの概念がありますが、
But what about his private content?
しかし、彼のプライベートなコンテンツはどうなるのでしょうか？
may not be the same
同じではないかもしれない
What if I use this example
この例を使うとどうなるでしょうか
Let me tell you about tomorrow
明日のことを話しましょう
Actually, I am not talking about architecture with outsiders today.
実は今日私は部外者と建築について話しているわけではありません。
Maybe when it comes to architecture, everyone here may be more suitable to talk about than me.
もしかしたら、建築に関しては私よりもここにいる皆さんの方が話すのに適しているかもしれません。
Then I just want to understand with you
それなら私はあなたと一緒に理解したいだけです
What I mean to explain to you is this
私があなたに説明したいことはこれです
Such a study of privacy
このようなプライバシーの研究
In fact, it's not just limited to my Chinese law.
実際、これは私の中国の法律に限定されたものではありません。
In fact, everyone in society should care about him
実際、社会の誰もが彼のことを気にかけるべきです
His appearance because of privacy
プライバシーのため彼の外見
We're going to learn about a society at a time
私たちは一度に社会について学びます
when was his privacy view
プライバシーに関する彼の見解はいつでしたか
Actually we
実は私たち
There may be a lot to see
見るべきものがたくさんあるかもしれない
Not just the so-called counting system at that time
当時のいわゆるカウントシステムだけではなく
what does his law say
彼の法律は何と言っていますか
or his organizational design
または彼の組織設計
Probably more important to look at his life
おそらく彼の人生を見つめることの方が重要だろう
How do they live in normal daily life?
彼らは普通の日常生活をどのように送っているのでしょうか？
See them from the midst of his daily life
日常生活の中から彼らを見つめる
what they care what they don't care
彼らが気にしていること、気にしていないこと
Then we can understand
そうすれば理解できる
In terms of that society, what they presented at that time
あの社会にあの時彼らが提示したもの
Where did they put the connotation of privacy?
彼らはプライバシーという意味合いをどこに置いたのでしょうか?
so i basically
だから私は基本的に
Although today I want to talk to you about privacy and privacy
今日はプライバシーとプライバシーについて話したいと思いますが、
But I really wanted to tell you from the beginning
でも本当は最初から言いたかったんだ
In fact, what I want to talk about today is limited.
実は今日話したいことは限られています。
I'm just speaking from my lawyer's point of view
私は弁護士の観点から話しているだけです
In fact, there may be more that can be cut into the surface
実際には、表面に切り込めるものはさらにあるかもしれません
Then this study
それからこの研究は
Because I have been engaged in this research for quite a long time
私はこの研究に長年携わってきたので、
Then this kind of research
それから、このような研究
Of course, domestic research is relatively
もちろん国内の研究は比較的
not very hot and weak
あまり熱くなくて弱い
Then if you read some foreign research
そこで海外の研究を読んでみると、
You can see that foreign research is very
海外の研究が非常に進んでいることがわかります。
He has a very broad entry point
彼は非常に幅広いエントリーポイントを持っています
That makes me very envious
それはとても羨ましいです
They can come from many places like we just talked about
先ほど話したように、彼らはさまざまな場所から来る可能性があります
It's a building they might talk about life
それは彼らが人生について語るかもしれない建物です
He looks at it from different places
彼はそれをさまざまな場所から見ています
their society or a certain society
彼らの社会、あるいは特定の社会
what is that privacy concept
そのプライバシー概念とは何ですか
But if you go back to Taiwan and look at our own research in Taiwan
しかし、台湾に戻って、台湾での私たちの研究を見てみると、
What about these parts? Relatively speaking, it is relatively
こういった部分はどうでしょうか? 相対的に言えば、
Few people do research in this area
この分野を研究する人はほとんどいません
So I also hope to say what I said in today's speech.
ですから、私も今日のスピーチで述べたことを申し上げたいと思います。
able to evoke what you are doing
自分がやっていることを呼び起こすことができる
interested in this thing
このことに興味がある
And then we can look at it from a different perspective, a different perspective
そうすれば、私たちはそれを別の方法で、別の方法で見ることができます。
or from different scholars
または別の学者からの
It can be cut into the research that is done, if this is the case
そうなった場合、行われている研究にそれが含まれる可能性があります
we're going to talk about privacy on this
これについてはプライバシーについて話します
His content will be richer
彼のコンテンツはより充実したものになるだろう
Then I will do a little bit of my personal research today.
それでは、今日は個人的な調査を少ししてみます。
A cut-in from my personal research
私の個人的な研究からのカットイン
Then go further into some of the results of my research so far
次に、これまでの私の研究結果のいくつかをさらに詳しく見ていきます
I will give you a little report
ちょっとしたご報告をさせていただきます
let's talk
話しましょう
From a lawyer's point of view From my personal point of view as a lawyer
弁護士の視点から 弁護士としての私の個人的な視点から
When we are doing other legal people
他の法人をやっている場合
Not everyone has a different opinion
全員が違う意見を持っているわけではない
I'm just speaking from my personal point of view
あくまで私の個人的な観点から話しているだけです
Let me explain to you
説明させてください
what is privacy what is privacy
プライバシーとは何ですか プライバシーとは何ですか
then what happened to it now
それで今はどうなったのか
Now it's the consulting society
今はコンサルティング協会です
what happened in the middle of the consulting society
コンサルティング会の真ん中で何が起こったのか
What about these things? From the legal person's point of view
法人の観点から、これらについてはどうですか？
From my point of view as a lawyer
弁護士としての私の視点から
Why do you think the current law
なぜ現在の法律だと思いますか
the current rule of law on privacy
プライバシーに関する現在の法の規則
There are deficiencies in the legal norms
法的規範に不備がある
then what we say about such things
では、そのようなことについて私たちは何を言うのか
how should
どのようにすべき
how to look at such a thing
そんなものをどうやって見るか
That's probably what I'm going to talk to you about today.
おそらくそれが今日私が皆さんに話そうとしていることです。
wait a minute
ちょっと待って
Talk to us about privacy first
まずはプライバシーについてご相談ください
That
それか
I'm offering you a
あなたに1つ提供します
one
一個
you may not have noticed
あなたは気づいていないかもしれません
Everyone, let's talk about privacy first.
皆さん、まずプライバシーについて話しましょう。
everyone talks about privacy
誰もがプライバシーについて話します
if talking about privacy
プライバシーについて話す場合
you can think of
あなたは考えることができます
privacy
プライバシー
May be Privacy
プライバシーかもしれない
Outside Privacy
Privacy外
or Privacy
またはプライバシー
or a different way of thinking
あるいは別の考え方
But it's Privacy
でもそれはプライバシーです
That
それか
why does it make me feel like saying
なぜ言いたくなるのか
This Privacy translates into privacy
このプライバシーはプライバシーに変換されます
Or privacy is to do Privacy
あるいはプライバシーはプライバシーを行うことです
has a problem
問題があります
because if i
なぜなら、もし私が
If all of us can understand
私たち全員が理解できれば
It means our Jingling
それは私たちのジャラジャラという意味です
statue japan
像日本
or Korea
または韓国
same with
と同じ
Words in the middle of traditional culture, society and culture
伝統文化、社会、文化の真ん中にある言葉
is subject to
の対象となる
probably influenced by our culture
おそらく私たちの文化の影響を受けているでしょう
The source is about the same
ソースはほぼ同じ
But the words of their society are strange
しかし、彼らの社会の言葉は奇妙です
When they also encounter Privacy
プライバシーに遭遇した場合
They didn't translate it into an equivalent word in Japanese
彼らはそれを日本語で同等の単語に翻訳しませんでした
Korean is the same no
韓国人も同じだよ
relatively speaking
比較的言えば
They used the so-called foreign language
彼らはいわゆる外国語を使用しました
What about his words in his pinyin?
彼の言葉のピンインはどうでしょうか？
Go and translate that Privacy into
行ってプライバシーを次のように翻訳してください
spelled his Japanese
彼の日本語を綴った
or in Korean
または韓国語で
relatively strange
比較的奇妙な
Then why do we translate Privacy into privacy in Taiwan?
では、なぜ台湾ではプライバシーをプライバシーと訳すのでしょうか？
Hong Kong turned it into private printing
香港は民間印刷に変えた
What about mainland China and Macau?
中国本土とマカオはどうですか？
all turned into privacy
すべてがプライバシーに変わった
it's weird
それは奇妙だ
In the Chinese world
中華世界では
we will say categorically
私たちはきっぱりと言います
we just have
私たちはただ持っています
In the middle of Chinese, there are words that can
中国語の真ん中には、次のような言葉があります。
To show that it is equivalent to this Privacy
本プライバシーに相当するものであることを示すため
same
同じ
in Japan or in Korea
日本でも韓国でも
why didn't they do something like this
なぜ彼らはこのようなことをしなかったのか
why is it like this
なぜこんなことになっているのか
Are we starting to touch
触れ始めていますか
When the word Privacy
プライバシーという言葉が出るとき
When we are going to translate it into Chinese
それを中国語に翻訳しようとすると、
China at that time
当時の中国
Chinese
中文
What about in our Chinese world?
私たちの中国語世界ではどうでしょうか？
In fact, there are corresponding words
実は対応する言葉があるんです
It corresponds to this Privacy
このプライバシーに該当します
So we apply it
それでそれを適用します
is it so
そうですか
This is what caused me to
これが私に起こった原因です
why this
なぜこれ
one reason to study him
彼を研究する一つの理由
Of course through this
もちろんこれを通して
we can go up slowly
私たちはゆっくり登ることができます
I was talking just now
たった今話してたんだ
because every society
なぜならどの社会でも
He has a concept of privacy
彼はプライバシーの概念を持っています
So by saying like this
だからこう言うことで
In fact, if we understand that
実際、それが理解できれば、
This Privacy is equal to privacy
このプライバシーはプライバシーに等しい
Then we also want to pass
それなら私たちも合格したいです
What about the word privacy?
プライバシーという言葉についてはどうでしょうか？
to see in our traditional society
私たちの伝統的な社会で見ること
so far
ここのところ
What is our view on privacy
プライバシーについての当社の見解
What is our view on this privacy
このプライバシーについて私たちはどう考えていますか
I also want to
私もしたい
in this regard
この点について
also want to do a little research
私も少し調べてみたいと思います
But first I can tell you some conclusions
しかし、最初に結論をいくつかお話します
because the process is not over yet
プロセスはまだ終わっていないので
Because the process is quite long
かなり工程が長いので
There is a way to talk to you like this, if you talk like this, everyone may not be interested
こんな話し方があるなら、こんな話し方したら、みんな興味ないかもしれない
but
しかし
From the middle of this kind of research, I just talked about this
こういった研究の途中から、先ほどこんな話をしました。
Especially when I saw the words of the vice president here, I said
特にここで副大統領の言葉を見たとき、私はこう言いました。
I am from a lawyer's point of view
私は弁護士の立場から考えています
I'm not from a historian's point of view so the middle of the report
私は歴史家の観点ではないので、レポートの途中です
If you think history is not interpreted this way, please tell me too
歴史はこのように解釈されていないと思うなら、私にも教えてください
Then this will involve, in fact, there are also linguistic issues in it.
それから、これには実は言語的な問題も絡んできます。
In addition to the historical linguistics just mentioned, if we
先ほど述べた歴史言語学に加えて、
If it is expanded a bit, sociology and anthropology may both be required.
もう少し拡張すると、社会学と人類学が両方必要になるかもしれません。
This should be fine
これでいいはずです
should be able to contribute or should be able to happen
貢献できるはず、あるいは実現できるはずだ
I'll start with the conclusion
結論から言います
We believe
我々は信じている
We came into contact with the word Privacy at that time
プライバシーという言葉に出会ったあの時
then turn it into privacy
それをプライバシーに変える
Because of
なぜなら
The words of our society at that time were considered to be said
当時の私たちの社会が言ったと思われる言葉
The word "privacy" in the Chinese world
中国語圏の「プライバシー」という言葉
It is corresponding to the Privacy in English
英語のPrivacyに対応
I never said it was wrong before
今までそれが間違っているとは一度も言ったことはありません
In fact, when I first came into contact with
実は、初めて触れたとき、
What about Privacy?
プライバシーについてはどうですか?
I so far some of our
私はこれまでのところ、私たちの一部を
I have done some analysis so far
これまでにいくつかの分析を行ってきました
Did not immediately translate him into privacy
彼をすぐにプライバシーに移さなかった
no that's surprising
いや、それは驚くべきことだ
This lasted until after the 1970s
これは1970年代以降まで続きました
we're just getting started
私たちはまだ始まったばかりです
Really start to think that privacy can be privacy
プライバシーはプライバシーであり得ると本当に考え始めます
Privacy equals Privacy
プライバシーはプライバシーに等しい
This process is quite a long time
このプロセスはかなり時間がかかります
does not mean that the middle
真ん中という意味ではありません
No one treats Privacy as privacy
誰もプライバシーをプライバシーとして扱いません
not like this
こんなんじゃない
It means that he will become
それは彼がなるということです
when there is no problem
問題がないとき
Probably after the 1970s
おそらく1970年代以降
at least in taiwan
少なくとも台湾では
So in order to think about this
そこで、これを考えるために
we also did one thing
私たちも一つのことをしました
let him go
彼を手放す
because to find
見つけるため
just find the earliest
一番早いものを見つけてください
to see if anyone found
誰かが見つけたかどうかを確認するために
The earliest Yin-Han dictionary
最古の陰漢辞書
then we have to do this
それならこれをしなければなりません
Just look at the English-Chinese dictionary at that time.
当時の英中辞典を見てみましょう。
What does he mean by Privacy in Chinese?
中国語でプライバシーとは何というのでしょうか?
What about at the same time?
同時にはどうでしょうか？
we also want to know
私たちも知りたいです
Privacy at that time was in the English-speaking world
当時の英語圏におけるプライバシー
words of the english world
英語世界の言葉
What do they mean by Privacy
プライバシーとは何を意味しますか
that of course some current words
もちろん最近の言葉も
what is done is still limited
できることはまだ限られている
We used Oxford
オックスフォードを使用しました
His English in Oxford
オックスフォードでの彼の英語力
That Dishonernary
その不正行為
what about looking for
探してみてはどうでしょうか
We can see that at least in 1900
少なくとも 1900 年にはそれがわかります
then we can see
そうすればわかります
they go back to words
彼らは言葉に戻ります
An Oxford like this
こんなオックスフォード
English in Oxford
オックスフォードの英語
Words in Dishonernary
不法行為の言葉
When he said the word Privacy
彼がプライバシーという言葉を言ったとき
He will say that it is actually from earlier
彼は実はそれはもっと前のことだと言うだろう
Thanks
ありがとう
that's what they say
それが彼らが言うことです
In fact, what about the word Privacy?
実際、プライバシーという言葉はどうでしょうか?
from
から
In the middle of the English-speaking world, it was between 191600 and 1700
英語圏の真ん中では、191600 年から 1700 年の間でした。
You can probably see that a lot of texts use the word Privacy
おそらく、多くのテキストで「プライバシー」という言葉が使用されていることがわかります。
That includes Sasbija's work
これにはサスビアの作品も含まれます
Also use it like this later
後でこんな風にも使います
he used the word
彼はその言葉を使った
Then by 1919, at least after 1700, after 1700
それから 1919 年までに、少なくとも 1700 年以降、1700 年以降
What about this part? Maybe
この部分はどうでしょうか？
Use the word Privacy in the English world
英語圏ではプライバシーという言葉を使用する
just more and more more and more
ただもっともっともっともっと
So we still don't know when the word "he" first started.
したがって、「彼」という言葉がいつから始まったのかはまだわかりません。
But at least in 1600 there has been
しかし、少なくとも1600年には、
What about after 1700?
1700年以降はどうでしょうか？
he used the word
彼はその言葉を使った
Then he used the word
それから彼はその言葉を使いました
Then he used the word but said it already existed in 1600
それから彼はその言葉を使いましたが、それは1600年にはすでに存在していたと言いました。
What about after 1700?
1700年以降はどうでしょうか？
This word is probably very common in the English-speaking world.
この単語はおそらく英語圏では非常に一般的です。
That
それか
What does the word Privacy mean?
プライバシーという言葉は何を意味しますか?
According to this Ostford University some of their
このオストフォード大学によると、彼らの一部は
Induction, he thinks he has about six meanings
帰納法、彼は6つほどの意味があると考えている
But by 1900 they were saying
しかし1900年までに彼らはこう言いました
In fact, these six meanings
実はこの6つの意味は、
If from their analysis
彼らの分析によると
I think it refers to the words from 1700 to the present
1700年から現在までの言葉を指していると思います
By then 1900 words
それまでに1900単語
Probably two meanings
おそらく二つの意味がある
There are probably only two meanings left
おそらく二つの意味しか残っていない
Other words probably have become
他の言葉はおそらくこうなったでしょう
yes
はい
passed
合格した
or no longer commonly used
またはもう一般的には使用されていません
Those two meanings are commonly used
この2つの意味がよく使われます
That is to say, it may be a kind of solitary
つまり、一種の孤独なのかもしれない
The state or condition of being out of public notice
公告されていない状態または状態
is a right to choose
選択する権利です
That's a kind of rejection
それはある種の拒絶反応だよ
or freedom from interference or intrusion
または干渉や侵入からの自由
this is the first explanation
これが最初の説明です
the second explanation
2番目の説明
is to say
言うことです
Private or Personal Matters of the First Kind
第一種のプライベートまたは個人的な事項
is a secret
は秘密です
you can understand
あなたが理解できること
What about after that?
その後はどうですか？
Probably everyone
おそらく全員
It may be the word privacy that you first imagined.
あなたが最初に想像したのはプライバシーという言葉かもしれません。
In the middle of your mind now
今、心の真ん中で
Does it mean this kind of privacy?
こういうプライバシーって意味あるの？
think about it
考えてみてください
each of us mouth
私たち一人一人の口
Now everyone will talk about
これからみんなで話します
This is my privacy
これは私のプライバシーです
when we say this
私たちがこれを言うとき
what we think is my privacy
私たちが私のプライバシーだと思っていること
what is that privacy
そのプライバシーとは何ですか
This is not usually according to this Chinese wording
これは通常、この中国語の表現に従っていません
just in Chinese
ただ中国語で
don't be so stupid
そんなにバカにしないで
Why do you spend so much time doing research?
なぜ研究にそんなに多くの時間を費やすのですか？
Just follow the literal meaning of Chinese
中国語の文字通りの意味に従ってください
It's something I don't want others to know
他人には知られたくないことです
is it like this
こんな感じですか
In fact, of course, what else is there on the other hand?
実際、もちろん、その一方で他に何があるでしょうか？
Just now if you see what you just said
今、あなたが今言ったことを見たら
Ospo's his
オスポは彼のもの
words in english language
英語の単語
what he said
彼が言ったこと
he's not just talking about that
彼はそれについてだけ話しているのではありません
he also includes space
彼にはスペースも含まれます
I'm a space I don't want people to invade
私は人に侵入されたくない空間です
Everyone think about the building just mentioned
誰もが今言及した建物について考えます
that house house
あの家 家
The design of that room of the house
家のあの部屋のデザイン
the design of that room
その部屋のデザイン
Do you feel
あなたは感じますか
That kind of fits with my notion of privacy
それは私のプライバシーの概念と一致します
That said, my view of privacy
とはいえ、私のプライバシー観は
Not just saying a lot of things I don't want people to know
知られたくないことをたくさん言うだけではありません
May also include I must have a space
「スペースが必要です」も含まれる場合があります
to allow anyone to enter the space
誰でもその空間に入ることができるようにする
unless invited
誘われない限り
So this may be what you want to see
だからこれがあなたが見たいものかもしれません
After the 1970s
1970年代以降
Until now, Privacy in English
これまで英語でプライバシー
what about this word
この言葉はどうでしょうか
Is what he explained already a bit like this?
彼が説明した内容はすでにこんな感じでしょうか？
But it's also quite strange
しかし、それは非常に奇妙でもあります
What about in the Chinese world?
中華圏ではどうなのでしょうか？
what we saw
私たちが見たもの
what we found was looking for that
私たちが見つけたのはそれを探していた
Just now I reported to you
先ほどご報告させていただきました
Let's go find a Yin-Han dictionary
陰漢辞書を探しに行きましょう
But when looking for a Yin-Han dictionary?
しかし、陰漢辞書を探しているときはどうでしょうか?
The Yin-Han dictionary does not directly translate Privacy into
陰漢辞書では、プライバシーを直接訳すことはできません。
Privacy that everyone takes for granted now is not
今では誰もが当たり前だと思っているプラ​​イバシーはそうではありません
The most common one is to turn Privacy into
最も一般的なことは、プライバシーを
wet
濡れた
we'll keep him private
私たちは彼を秘密にしておきます
Then it becomes very
そうなるととてもなります
Very very strange
とてもとても奇妙な
or interesting
または興味深い
Then I'm cutting in from another angle
次に別の角度から切り込んでいきます
So that you can be more clear what I just said is that
私が今言ったことをより明確にしていただくために、
In fact, we now think
実際、私たちは今こう考えています
Privacy is privacy
プライバシーはプライバシーです
We just flip it over like this
このようにひっくり返すだけです
that's not that fast
それはそんなに速くない
A message I got from another legal person
他の法人から受け取ったメッセージ
The information provided just now may not be enough
今提供された情報では十分ではないかもしれません
because if anyone is interested
なぜなら興味のある人がいたら
If today is linguistics
今日が言語学なら
or literary
または文学的な
if interested
興味があれば
with more research
さらに研究を進めれば
may find out
分かるかもしれない
This information is not enough
この情報では十分ではありません
Or even the interpretation of this information is wrong
あるいは、この情報の解釈さえ間違っています
that's okay
大丈夫
I am now offering a view from a legal person
私は今、法人の立場からの意見を述べています。
What do we think of the legal person?
法人についてどう思いますか？
We learn from our legal textbooks
私たちは法律の教科書から学びます
Let's look at the journal papers
雑誌の論文を見てみよう
let's see what it means
それが何を意味するのか見てみましょう
If Privacy is called
プライバシーが呼ばれる場合
From the photographer's words, it stands to reason
写真家の言葉からすると、それは当然のことです
If in our legal person's
当社法人の場合
inside this textbook
この教科書の中に
or in the research we wrote about
または私たちが書いた研究の中で
What about the words in the middle of the paper?
紙の真ん中にある文字はどうでしょうか？
when he uses the word
彼がその言葉を使うとき
He should be a single shadow teacher right away, right?
すぐに一人影の先生になれるはずですよね？
What does it look like?
それはどのように見えますか？
just what i told you
私があなたに言ったことだけ
Why talk about the 1970s
なぜ 1970 年代について話すのか
probably later
おそらく後で
it may be possible to say
言えるかもしれない
It wasn't like this before
以前はこんなことなかったのに
Because
なぜなら
because we lawyers
なぜなら私たち弁護士は
These textbooks published
これらの教科書は出版されています
or drill some
またはいくつかのドリルを
What about the words among the published papers in these odd journals?
これらの奇妙なジャーナルに掲載された論文の言葉についてはどうでしょうか?
messages we found
私たちが見つけたメッセージ
can see
見える
not like this
こんなんじゃない
it's going to be slow
遅くなるだろう
glasses to the end words
最後までメガネ
what did it become
それは何になりましたか
become a photographer
写真家になる
the early days
早期
earliest
最も早い
we can see that means
それが意味することがわかります
if that he wrote that
もし彼がそれを書いたなら
odd journal paper
奇妙な雑誌の論文
or he is in the book
あるいは彼は本の中にいます
he us
彼は私たち
The reason why we can know is to say
なぜそれを知ることができるのかというと、
In fact, I want to talk about Private
実はプライベートな話をしたいのですが、
the word
言葉
The reason is because we start with
その理由は、から始めるからです。
Let's now look at the materials he used at that time
当時使われていた資料を見てみましょう
information in english
英文的資料
We can tell he wants to use the word Privacy
彼がプライバシーという言葉を使いたがっているのがわかります
But then
しかしその後
first translated words
最初に翻訳された単語
He didn't translate him as Privacy
彼はプライバシーとは訳さなかった
turned into privacy
プライバシーに変わった
he turned him into a secret
彼は彼を秘密にした
turned into a secret
秘密に変わった
that turned into a secret
それは秘密になった
Then later words gradually slowly changed from secret
その後の言葉は徐々に秘密から徐々に変化していきました
just started to become private
プライベートになり始めたばかり
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
why is it funny
なぜ面白いのか
If we start from another entry point
別のエントリーポイントから始めると
We do not start from the word Privacy
私たちはプライバシーという言葉から始まるわけではありません
but from
しかし、から
everyone knows
みんな知ってる
this
これ
Maybe you are not so clear
たぶんあなたはあまり明確ではないでしょう
but i can tell you
しかし、私はあなたに言うことができます
Taiwan's Civil and Criminal Law
台湾の民法と刑法
Basically
基本的
Everyone says we are a civil law system
誰もが私たちは民法制度だと言っています
Many of you can understand
理解できる方も多いでしょう
civil law
市民法
We are not a legal system
私たちは法制度ではありません
Under the context of the civil law system,
民法制度の文脈では、
our in
私たちの中で
It's in the civil law
それは民法にある
is also subject to
も対象となります
Logically speaking, it is also a civil law system
論理的に言えば民法の制度でもあります
The legal system is based on this tradition
法制度はこの伝統に基づいています
As for the civil law system, there probably is one
民法制度に関しては、おそらく一つあります。
probably related to the privacy we're going to talk about today
おそらく今日お話しするプライバシーに関係するでしょう
right of personality
人格権
personality rights section or torts section
人格権セクションまたは不法行為セクション
Then we go to the early
それから早めに行きます
Textbook of Civil Law
民法教科書
As for the civil law textbooks, at the earliest time, of course we
民法の教科書については、もちろん早い段階で
Just find Mr. Shi Changhuan, and then become a possible legal person
Shi Changhuan氏を見つけて、法人候補者になるだけです
Mr. Shi Changhuan
石長環さん
That Mr. Shi Changhuan first used
Shi Changhuan氏が最初に使用したもの
in his textbook
彼の教科書には
What about the words in his textbook? He is using
彼の教科書の単語はどうですか? 彼は使っています
In the
の中に
In fact, he wants to explain what personality rights are
実際、彼は人格権とは何かを説明したいと考えています
or infringement
または侵害
The part that infringes on personality rights
人格権を侵害する部分
As a result, two words suddenly appeared in him.
その結果、彼の中に突然二つの言葉が浮かんだ。
is a secret
は秘密です
secret
秘密
He just said something in the middle of this type of human rights violation
この種の人権侵害の最中に彼は何かを言ったばかりだ
there are secrets in it
そこには秘密があります
The word secret is actually the same as
秘密という言葉は実際には次と同じです。
if we say this
私たちがこれを言うなら
It's actually the same as the privacy we're going to talk about today.
実はこれは、今日お話しするプライバシーと同じことなのです。
But they're called secrets
でもそれらは秘密と呼ばれる
So on the other hand
それで、一方で
We can see another tradition
別の伝統を見ることができます
That is the tradition of the civil law system
それが民法制度の伝統です
traditional words in civil law systems
民法体系における伝統的な用語
speaks this part of german
ドイツ語のこの部分を話します
words in this part of germany
ドイツのこの地域の言葉
I have to tell you here too
ここでも言わなければなりません
Today we talk about privacy called Privacy
今日はプライバシーというプライバシーについて話します
Privacy is privacy
プライバシーはプライバシーです
But when we say
しかし、私たちが言うとき
It's Privacy under the English-speaking world
英語圏ではプライバシーです
Let me tell you a little bit more
もう少し詳しくお話しさせてください
In fact, the word Privacy
実際、プライバシーという言葉は、
in german or in french
ドイツ語かフランス語で
At least the one I asked didn't have the same word
少なくとも私が尋ねたものは同じ言葉を持っていませんでした
no same word
同じ言葉はありません
Of course they express it in other ways
もちろん他の方法でも表現します
same concept
同じコンセプト
so today we
だから今日私たちは
Strange
変
I mean Taiwan
台湾のことです
Mainland China
中国本土
Hong Kong
香港
Macau
マカオ
South Korea
韓国
Or use Privacy in Japan
または、日本ではプライバシーを使用してください
Privacy is used in many places
プライバシーは多くの場所で使用されます
then directly
それから直接
adopted the traditions directly from here
ここの伝統から直接
Traditions on the side of Anglo-American law
英米法の側にある伝統
The traditional words of German law become another
ドイツ法の伝統的な言葉が別のものになる
But here the words are in this
しかし、ここにこの言葉が入っています
The words on this, this, this topic, on this topic
この、この、このトピック、このトピックに関する言葉
The last thing we saw was a stream
最後に見たのは小川だった
Meeting stream becomes a privacy again
会議ストリームが再びプライバシーに
So let's look at what we just talked about
それでは、今話した内容を見てみましょう
from if from this civil law system
この民法制度からの場合
If German law comes here
もしドイツの法律がここに来たら
it's a secret
それは秘密です
What about the last word?
最後の言葉はどうでしょうか？
Slowly it turns into privacy
徐々にプライバシーに変わります
over here
ここに
we just started talking about
私たちはちょうど話し始めたばかりです
We see that originally it was meant to say
元々はこう言うつもりだったことがわかります
The relevant information of the word Privacy
プライバシーという言葉の関連情報
The words about these things come from Anglo-American law.
これらに関する言葉は英米法に由来しています。
What about here?
ここはどうですか？
In fact, Anglo-American law may be too broad
実際、英米法は広すぎる可能性がある
It should be about American law.
それはアメリカの法律に関するものであるはずです。
What about over here?
ここはどうですか？
Privacy was originally translated as secret
プライバシーはもともと秘密と訳されました
why it turned into a secret
なぜ秘密になったのか
Is it because when the time was 1950
時代が1950年だからでしょうか？
In the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s
1940 年代、1950 年代、1960 年代
In fact, in our legal circle
実際、私たちの法曹界では
So in terms of that related concept, I think he is going to
関連するコンセプトに関して言えば、彼は次のようになると思います。
secret
ひみつ
But then slowly it became private
しかしその後、徐々にプライベートになりました
It's a fun place to say I can't help it
仕方ないと言うのが楽しいところです。
find more
もっと見つけます
Let me explain with more information
詳しい情報を交えて説明しましょう
Why was it 1960s and 70s, especially that
特に 1960 年代と 70 年代はなぜだったのか
Why did that transformation in the 1970s start to become
1970 年代のその変革はなぜ起こり始めたのか
used to tell secrets
秘密を話すために使われていた
So why now suddenly we need to use another
では、なぜ今突然別のものを使用する必要があるのでしょうか?
The word called privacy to replace the secret?
秘密に代わる言葉はプライバシーと呼ばれます
not sure
不太清楚
However, if the media
ただし、メディアであれば、
It's what journalism scholars and communication scholars talk about
それはジャーナリズム学者やコミュニケーション学者が話していることです
They feel that the credit is on their side and cannot be credited.
彼らは、功績は自分たちの側にあるのに、功績として認められるはずがない、と感じています。
That is to say, I will watch it at that time
つまりその時は観ます
That was the time when newspapers and magazines, they started more
当時は新聞や雑誌がもっと普及し始めた時期でした。
reporting some
いくつか報告する
foreign news, foreign news inside
外国のニュースが海外のニュースになっているとき
Perhaps the most reported ones are probably the news from the United States.
おそらく最も多く報道されているのは米国からのニュースでしょう
There may be more words in the news, just like now
今みたいにニュースでもっと言葉が出てくるかもしれない
At present, it may be that some societies
現時点では、一部の社会では、
or some
またはいくつか
Some news about some famous people and politicians
有名人や政治家に関するニュース
If it involves news about politicians and famous people
政治家や著名人に関するニュースの場合
What must everyone want to see more?
誰もが見たいものは何ですか？
It may be related to his Privacy
それは彼のプライバシーに関連している可能性があります
If he got it over here
彼がここでそれを手に入れたら
Maybe they just turned it into Privacy
おそらく彼らはそれをプライバシーに変えただけかもしれません
maybe it means
たぶんそれは意味する
The word Privacy is translated into secret words
プライバシーという言葉は秘密の言葉に翻訳されます
Maybe they got it over there
たぶん彼らはあそこでそれを手に入れた
they don't think it's enough
彼らはそれが十分だとは思っていない
not enough
十分でない
when you're just telling a secret
ただ秘密を話しているとき
They will feel that telling the secret should be an understanding
彼らは秘密を話すことが理解であるべきだと感じるでしょう
like this
このような
But what about privacy?
しかし、プライバシーについてはどうでしょうか?
Maybe his scope is a little bit more than secret
もしかしたら彼の守備範囲は秘密以上のものなのかもしれない
we are not sure
私たちにはわかりません
so let's go back and see
それで戻って見てみましょう
In fact, the word privacy
実際、プライバシーという言葉は、
words in the chinese world
中国語の世界の言葉
What about in our traditional culture?
私たちの伝統文化ではどうでしょうか？
Is there any way we can find these two words
この 2 つの単語を見つける方法はありますか?
what does he mean
彼はどういう意味ですか
Then we can see that the earliest words
すると、最初の言葉が
The two words "hidden" and "lost" were separated very early
「隠された」と「失われた」という 2 つの単語はかなり早い段階で分離されました
Appeared very early in the Chinese world
中国世界では非常に早くから登場した
But what if these two words are connected together?
しかし、これら 2 つの単語が一緒に接続されたらどうなるでしょうか?
exist
存在
It was mentioned in the Spring and Autumn Period of the Warring States Period
春秋戦国時代に記録あり。
But it's funny when he mentions it. He's called
でも彼がそのことを言うと面白いのです。
the winner wins or loses
勝者が勝つか負けるか
win or lose
勝つか負けるか
What does it mean? What is winning means losing?
どういう意味ですか? 勝つということは負けるということですか?
That's the two words? He seems to agree.
それがその 2 つの言葉ですか? 彼も同意しているようです。
agree
同意
But he changed these two words into saying win or lose
でも彼はこの2つの言葉を勝ち負けという言葉に変えた
he called win
彼は勝利と呼んだ
lost too
も失った
So he is using
それで彼は使っています
to explain what
何を説明するために
What is winning and losing?
勝ち負けとは何でしょうか？
just win
ただ勝つだけ
That
それか
If we go to the instructions to explain
説明に従って説明すると、
When it comes to the explanation and explanation, let’s look at the explanation and explanation of Xu Sheng in the Eastern Han Dynasty
説明と説明に関しては、後漢時代の徐盛の説明と説明を見てみましょう
He came down from the front and down to him, at least up to the word he understood until then
彼は前から降りてきて、彼のところへ降りてきた、少なくともそれまで理解できた言葉までは
He also didn't combine winning with losing half
彼はまた、勝ちと半分負けを組み合わせなかった
At most, he just talked about winning and losing.
せいぜい勝ち負けについて話すだけだった。
what is he talking about at most? what is he talking about at most?
彼はせいぜい何を話しているのですか? せいぜい何を話しているのですか?
In fact, what are the words called?
実際、その言葉は何と呼ばれているのでしょうか？
just cover one up
一つだけカバーして
It's called shadow
それを影といいます
But apart from this more usual awareness
しかし、このより一般的な意識とは別に、
In addition, there are about thirty other consciousnesses.
さらに、他にも約 30 の意識が存在します。
shadow meaning
影的意思
However, the consciousness that has the most wishes for shadow names and names is shadows.
しかし、影の名前と名前に最も多くの願いを抱いている意識は影です。
private eye
私的な目
Then this has been like this since the Warring States Period
じゃあ戦国時代からこうだったのか
If you really want to connect these two words together
本当にこの 2 つの単語を結び付けたい場合は、
The information we have found so far
これまでに判明した情報
I can only see that it was in the Northern and Southern Dynasties
南北朝時代にしか見えない
during the two dynasties
二つの王朝の間に
a word we see
私たちが目にする言葉
Should it be about the father or the word
父親のことなのか、言葉のことなのか
a word is used in it
その中である言葉が使われている
The two words called "shadow private" are connected together
「シャドウプライベート」という二つの言葉がつながっている
But at that time
でもその時は
Let's look at the time when the two words are connected together
二つの言葉が繋がる瞬間を見てみましょう
what is its consciousness
その意識は何なのか
Consciousness is talking about husband and wife
意識は夫婦について話している
something in the middle of defense
防御の途中で何か
Call shadow private
シャドウプライベートを呼び出します
other than this
これ以外の
If we do some more analysis
もう少し分析してみると
we can probably see
おそらく見えるでしょう
except us
私たちを除いて
just talked about this
ちょうどこれについて話しました
this
これ
that is, between husband and wife
つまり夫婦の間で
These situations between men and women
男女間のこうした状況
called privacy
プライバシーという
Then there are probably two more, and three others. There are four in total.
それから、おそらくあと 2 つ、あと 3 つ、合計 4 つあります。
We all seem more common
私たちは皆、もっと普通に見える
If we count
数えてみたら
at least to
少なくとも
Late Qing Dynasty 190 19
清末190 19
It is equal to the mid-19th century in the late Qing Dynasty
清朝末期の19世紀半ばに相当します。
Let's see what's going on in the middle, except what I just said
私が今言ったことを除いて、真ん中で何が起こっているのか見てみましょう
there is another
もう一つの...がある
dark secret
暗い秘密
My secret is also called privacy
私の秘密はプライバシーとも呼ばれます
The third kind of words, he does not have any positive
3 番目の種類の言葉、彼にはポジティブな言葉がありません。
or the secret of negative reviews
または否定的なレビューの秘密
secret
秘密
As for the fourth type, there are actually more of them.
4 番目のタイプは実際にはさらに多くのものです
as long as it raises something that might be worth discussing
議論する価値があるかもしれない何かを提起する限り
He is a clean person, we often talk about it when we see it
彼はきれいな人で、会うたびによくその話をします。
Clean privacy Clean privacy
クリーンなプライバシー クリーンなプライバシー
But when we watch him clean his privacy, we pay attention
しかし、彼がプライバシーを掃除しているのを見ると、私たちは注意を払います
at that time
その時
What words do you use?
どのような言葉を使いますか？
Its privacy is related to privacy
そのプライバシーはプライバシーに関連しています
cloudy cloudy
曇り
Yin and private two are used at the same time
陰とプライベートの2つは同時に使用されます
So this privacy and privacy
ですから、このプライバシーとプライバシーは
Everyone thinks of what privacy and privacy mean to you
あなたにとってプライバシーとプライバシーが何を意味するのか誰もが考えています
what's your impression
あなたの印象は何ですか
Is insidiousness more negative?
陰湿さはよりネガティブですか？
privacy seems like
プライバシーはこんな感じ
It seems nothing special
特別なことは何もないようです
But tell me
でも教えて
until at least
少なくとも
When we come into contact with the word Privacy
プライバシーという言葉に触れたとき
There's nothing wrong with having privacy back then
当時はプライバシーに何の問題もなかった
also have privacy
プライバシーもあります
And privacy and privacy are used together
そしてプライバシーとプライバシーは併用される
Then we can also see
そうすれば、私たちも見ることができます
If it will continue to develop at the end of the Qing Dynasty
清朝末期も発展し続けるなら
to the Republic of China
中華民国へ
Also these two words are also in our newspaper
この二つの言葉も新聞に載っています
or even on paperwork
あるいは書類上でも
I have seen the word privacy
プライバシーという言葉を見たことがある
So we can understand that by saying
したがって、次のように理解できます。
When the word Privacy was introduced
プライバシーという言葉が登場したとき
Actually at that time
実はあの時
And we have no privacy for these two Chinese words
そして、この 2 つの中国語の単語についてはプライバシーがありません
the word of these two words
この二つの言葉の言葉
Existed at that time, not non-existent
当時は存在した、存在しなかった
So it's also strange that he didn't
だから彼がそうしなかったのも不思議だ
PrivacyTranslate to this
プライバシーこちらに翻訳
When speaking Chinese, he did not choose
中国語を話すとき、彼は選択しませんでした
privacy that already existed
すでに存在するプライバシー
So it's also an interesting one
だからそれも面白いんです
why is it like this
なぜこんなことになっているのか
It is also worth our continued thinking
私たちが考え続ける価値もあります
But what I wanted to tell you just now is to say
でも今言いたかったのは、
whether he is
彼がいるかどうか
even then
その時でさえ
Or that I just researched
それとも私が調べただけなのか
is wrong
間違っている
Anyway, Privacy turned over is privacy
とにかく、ひっくり返されたプライバシーはプライバシーです
This privacy word is literally
このプライバシーという言葉は文字通り、
I just don't want others to know
ただ他人に知られたくないだけ
private matter
個人的な問題
plus a little personal space
プラス少しのパーソナルスペース
Then this word is the same as the word Privacy in English at that time
そうするとこの言葉は当時の英語のPrivacyという言葉と同じです。
Even now the word is actually the same
今でもその言葉は実は同じ
Even though I just said that even if we have the same
先ほども言いましたが、たとえ同じものを持っていたとしても
concept
概念
In fact, if you look at the wisdom of Chinese
実際、中国人の知恵を見てみると、
over there privacy or privacy
あそこのプライバシーかプライバシーか
or secret or something
それとも秘密か何か
In fact, we all have the concept of privacy
実際、私たちは皆プライバシーの概念を持っています
It's just that we may not be useful
ただ、私たちは役に立たないかもしれないというだけです
Privacy as everyone understands it now
今では誰もが理解しているプラ​​イバシー
that subfield also describes it
そのサブフィールドもそれを説明します
Then we might have to explain to you
それから、あなたに説明しなければならないかもしれません
Even if we use the same words now
今同じ言葉を使っても
called privacy
プライバシーという
But you have to understand
しかし、それを理解する必要があります
even with the same word
同じ言葉でも
its at different times
それは異なる時間にあります
or in different societies
あるいは異なる社会で
The reason why it advocates the concept of privacy
プライバシーの概念を提唱する理由
Its possible function and purpose
その考えられる機能と目的
may not be exactly the same
まったく同じではないかもしれません
so our
だから私たちの
Huang Kewu who entered the teacher's institute
師範学校に入学した黄克武さん
Director Huang once did some research
黄監督はかつて調査したことがある
I think he's a study
彼は勉強家だと思う
In the end he said something that said
最後に彼はこんなことを言いました
Actually even though we have the same noun
実は同じ名詞でも
but
しかし
content of the concept
コンセプトの内容
Especially from its function and purpose
特にその機能と目的から
if it goes in
それが入ったら
We can see that it is actually different
実際には違うことがわかります
Especially when it comes to privacy
特にプライバシーに関しては
our privacy
私たちのプライバシー
Maybe it's just saying that I don't want others to know
もしかしたら他人に知られたくないと言っているだけなのかもしれない
I don't want people in my space
自分の空間に人を入れたくない
But if we can learn
しかし、もし私たちが学ぶことができれば、
Said that we will go to see this matter again today
今日もう一度この件を見に行くと言いました
You may not simply say
単純に言うことはできないかもしれません
I don't want others to know
他人に知られたくない
I don't want anyone to know come in
誰にも知られたくない
And maybe when we say these words
そしておそらく私たちがこれらの言葉を言うとき
In fact, there is another meaning
実はもう一つ意味があるのです
that is the modern sense
それが現代の感覚だ
It's just that there may be some individualistic concepts coming in.
ただ、個人主義的な概念が入ってくる可能性もあります。
that early words
その初期の言葉
Maybe it doesn't have that idea
もしかしたらそういう発想はないのかもしれない
The idea that it changes is over there
変わるという考えはそこにある
it simply says
それは単に言うだけです
I don't want others to know
他人に知られたくない
But is there a behind it
でもその裏には何かあるのか
modern sense
現代的な感覚
The reason why I don't want others to know
他人に知られたくない理由
don't want to make others angry
他人を怒らせたくない
In fact, he has a very positive meaning
実際、彼には非常にポジティブな意味があります
That positive means
そのポジティブな意味は、
this is what i want to prove
これが私が証明したいことです
i am an autonomous
私は自律型です
self-determining
自己決定的な
i can be the one who chooses
私が選ぶことができる
In this case maybe
この場合、もしかしたら
That meaning may not have been in the early days
その意味は初期にはなかったかもしれない
I don't know if you guys are thinking about privacy right now
皆さんが今プライバシーについて考えているかどうかはわかりません。
this is my privacy time
これは私のプライバシーの時間です
When you say this word
この言葉を言うと
Apart from saying that this is the standby of the warm knife
これが温かいナイフのスタンバイだということは別として
this is mine
これは私のものです
This is my space, you don't come in, you don't care about these things
ここは私のスペースです、あなたは入ってはいけません、あなたはこれらのことを気にしません
It's a matter of asking people to take care of it or not
それは人々にそれを世話してもらうかどうかの問題です
other than this
これ以外の
do you have another meaning
別の意味がありますか
This is my business
これは私のビジネスです
After this, I will be able to prove that
この後、私はそれを証明できるでしょう
I am an individual that exists alone and meaningfully
私は孤独で有意義に存在する個人です
Does it mean something like this
こういう意味あるのかな
If I want to talk to you today about the concept of privacy, I want to tell you
今日、プライバシーの概念についてお話したいのであれば、次のことをお伝えしたいと思います。
In this way, I mainly want to tell you what I mean.
このように、主に私の言いたいことをお伝えしたいと思います。
Actually we are talking about privacy today
実は今日はプライバシーについて話しているのです
Privacy may be related to this Privacy
プライバシーはこのプライバシーに関連している可能性があります
the original English word
元々の英語の単語
the word in the world
世界の言葉
modern meaning
現代的な意味
about the same
ほぼ同じ
So Chinese choose to use privacy
だから中国人はプライバシーを利用することを選ぶ
Seems to be pretty good
かなり良いようです
it also satisfies
それも満足です
Literally interpreted from simplicity, it is very similar
単純さから文字通り解釈すると、非常に似ています
it's my private matter
それは私の個人的な問題です
My personal affairs don't need your intervention
私の個人的な問題にあなたの介入は必要ありません
Then let's add a little space concept into it.
次に、そこに空間の概念を少し加えてみましょう。
besides things
物以外にも
what else is there room
他に何の部屋がありますか
my space
私のスペース
the size of this space
この空間の大きさ
maybe it's because
たぶんそれは
The Contest I was in
私が参加したコンテスト
when the environment was different
環境が違ったとき
that maybe the size of that space
それはおそらくそのスペースのサイズです
may be a little different
少し違うかもしれません
everyone can understand
誰もが理解できる
If it is here today, it is very urgent on the MRT
今日ここにある場合、MRT では非常に緊急です
Of course there is no way to talk about that space
もちろんその空間について話すことはできません
don't get too close to me
私に近づきすぎないでください
if you get too close
近づきすぎると
Just invade my privacy, probably not
私のプライバシーを侵害するだけです、おそらくそうではありません
But if it's a very large space
しかし、それが非常に広い空間であれば、
of course of course
もちろんもちろん
What are you doing so close to your official document?
公式文書にそんなに近づいて何をしているのですか？
Why are the official documents so intimate?
なぜ公式文書はこれほど親密なものなのでしょうか？
You'll feel like there's a difference between
違いがあるように感じるでしょう
He said he was a relative concept
彼は自分は相対的な概念だと言いました
But the words here are worth thinking about again.
しかし、ここにある言葉も再考に値するものです。
It is very worthwhile for us to think about a question that is
という問いについて考えることは、私たちにとって非常に価値のあることです。
Why does every society have some concept of so-called privacy
なぜどの社会にもいわゆるプライバシーという概念があるのでしょうか
The content of this privacy may not be complete
このプライバシーの内容は完全ではない可能性があります
very specific may not be exactly the same
非常に具体的であるため、まったく同じではない可能性があります
For example, often
たとえば、多くの場合、
We often meet some new friends
私たちは新しい友達によく会います
will always want to say
常に言いたいでしょう
I'm curious
私は興味がある
how do you stay so young
どうやってそんなに若くいられるの？
you're probably only 18
あなたはおそらくまだ18歳です
start asking people's age
人の年齢を聞き始める
Wow you look like you are very accomplished
うわー、とても達成感があるように見えますね
how much money do you make every month
あなたは毎月いくら稼いでいますか
Then this may be in some societies
そうすると、これは一部の社会で起こるかもしれない
He doesn't think it's offensive
彼はそれが不快だとは思っていない
But in some societies
しかし、一部の社会では
I thought how could it be like this
どうしてこんなことになるんだろうと思った
it's none of your business
それはあなたの仕事ではありません
so the details
それで詳細は
Just do what you don't want others to know
他人に知られたくないことだけをする
we think it's reasonable
私たちはそれが合理的だと考えています
What things in that society feel to say
その社会で何を言うべきか
it's no big deal
それは大したことありません
so you'll notice
それで気づくでしょう
What about the very details?
非常に詳細についてはどうですか？
maybe it will be different
もしかしたら違うかもしれない
So this also aroused my curiosity to say
それで、これは私の好奇心を呼び起こしました。
How could it be like this?
どうしてこんなことになるのでしょうか？
Then let's think about another question slowly.
それでは、別の質問についてゆっくり考えてみましょう。
That
それか
Time is limited, I can simply use one word
時間は限られている、一言だけでいい
One sentence in the middle of Lun
ルン途中の一文
it just talks
それはただ話すだけです
non-gift event
ギフト以外のイベント
Non-gift story, non-gift is non-gift
贈り物ではない物語、贈り物ではないものは贈り物ではない
I can't sort it out like this
このように整理することはできません
maybe our
たぶん私たちの
Modern fathers and sons who are afraid of old people can be excreted
老人を恐れる現代の父と息子は排泄できる
what should be a gift
贈り物は何にすべきですか
Audio-visual serious audio-visual serious OK great
オーディオ・ビジュアル 深刻 オーディオ・ビジュアル 深刻 OK 素晴らしい
Probably everyone can know this, if you are in
おそらく、あなたがそこにいるなら誰もがこれを知っているでしょう
In the western world, it can be seen as a water monkey
西洋では水猿として見られることもある
Right or wrong?
正しいか間違っているか?
Mouth arms covered
口の腕が覆われている
Actually I think it's a good example
実際、それは良い例だと思います
This is in the middle of the Analects
論語の途中です
Empty words are not a thing he has said come out
空虚な言葉は彼が言ったものではない
It means that people may be in the middle of interaction
それは人々が交流の最中にいる可能性があることを意味します
He has at least one minimum thing
彼は少なくとも一つ最低限のものを持っている
His so-called unreasonable is not telling us not to see and not to listen
彼のいわゆる理不尽さは、私たちに見るな、聞くなと言っているのではありません。
It's a matter of reason
それは理由の問題です
Does it make sense?
意味はあるでしょうか？
That reason may be that society
その原則は社会なのかもしれない
Or the middle of his ideal society?
それとも彼の理想の社会の真ん中でしょうか？
what is
とは
Everyone should give respect to others
誰もが他人を尊重すべきです
there is a divide over there
そこには分裂がある
So we're going to continue our research
それで私たちは研究を続けるつもりです
you will talk
あなたは話します
What about every society?
それぞれの社会ではどうなのでしょうか？
What about the formation of his concept of privacy?
彼のプライバシーの概念の形成についてはどうですか？
Will follow the so-called social norms of the society at that time
その時の社会のいわゆる社会規範に従います
English is called social norms
英語は社会規範と呼ばれます
Then we translate it into words
それからそれを言葉に翻訳してみます
may be related to the social norms of the time
当時の社会常識と関係があるのか​​もしれない
may be related
関連するかもしれない
Maybe it has something to do with some morals in a society
もしかしたらそれは社会のモラルと関係があるのか​​もしれない
some notions of value
いくつかの価値観
may be related
関連するかもしれない
what about these words
この言葉はどうでしょうか
It may also be due to some time
時期のせいもあるかもしれないけど
this
これ
What about different or social changes?
異なる変化や社会的な変化についてはどうですか?
he may have something different
彼は何か違うものを持っているかもしれない
So we might as well understand this
したがって、私たちはこれを理解したほうがよいでしょう
When we want to understand our society
私たちの社会を理解したいとき
What about the concept of privacy in our society?
私たちの社会におけるプライバシーの概念はどうでしょうか?
In fact, we should be curious people to understand
実際、私たちは人々に理解してもらいたいと好奇心を持つべきです
most of our society
私たちの社会のほとんどが
There should be at least a division between people
少なくとも人々の間には分断が必要です
where is it
それはどこにある
how do we see
私たちはどうやって見るのですか
that this morning
今朝のこと
we hired a
私たちは人を雇いました
calligraphic calligraphy and painting art workers
書道・書画芸術家
also a guru
教祖でもある
Mr. Zhu Zhennan went to our so-called speech
朱振南氏は私たちのいわゆる演説会に行きました
Then what he said was
すると彼が言ったのは、
Outsiders can't
部外者には出来ない
Then he was talking about a
それから彼はあることについて話していました
That is to say, an interaction between our art and law
つまり、私たちの芸術と法律の間の相互作用です。
one thing he said
彼が言った一つのこと
Then I said that when he talked about this matter, he was very
それから私は、彼がこの件について話したとき、彼はとてもこう言ったと言いました。
He wondered how the society has come to this level
彼は社会がどうやってこのレベルに達したのか不思議に思った
He feels very aura
彼はとてもオーラを感じます
then I will talk to civilization
それから私は文明と話します
The deputy director said, very good, this is what I can talk about today.
副所長は、「とてもよかった。今日はこれについて話せます」と言いました。
A thing
一個東西
what did he say
彼が何を言ったの
He said that recently, everyone understands that it is not often
彼は、最近はそれが頻繁ではないことを誰もが理解していると言いました
This court thinks that
当法廷はこう考えている
There are too many reports of violations in this report case
この通報案件では違反の通報が多すぎます
Right? Then why are there so many reported cases?
そうですか? では、なぜこれほど多くの症例が報告されているのでしょうか?
It means that the police transferred a lot, so why did the police transfer
つまり、警察はたくさん異動しましたが、なぜ警察は異動したのですか？
There are so many because of why many people sue
訴訟が多いから訴訟する人が多いんだよ
many people report
多くの人が報告しています
What about now? In our society now
今はどうですか? 今私たちの社会では
There are many enthusiastic
熱心な方が多いです
But on the other hand, it is also possible that our law-breakers encourage such enthusiasm
しかしその一方で、法律違反者がそのような熱意を助長している可能性もあります。
So he started going around to report some things he couldn't get used to.
それで私は彼が慣れないいくつかのことを報告するために歩き始めました。
On the other hand, everyone thinks it should be good
一方で、誰もがそれが良いはずだと考えています
There should be some enthusiastic people in this society
この社会には熱狂的な人たちがいるはずだ
You should be very concerned about some social welfare matters
あなたは社会福祉の問題について非常に心配する必要があります
But from another perspective, he felt that there were so many accusations
しかし、別の観点から見ると、非常に多くの非難があったと彼は感じた
Why so many cups
なぜこんなにカップが多いのか
why so many of these things
なぜこんなにたくさんのことが
What about this matter?
この件についてはどうですか？
From another point of view?
別の観点から見ると？
In fact, it should be worthy of our concern
実際、それは私たちが懸念する価値があるはずです
How will our society and culture develop?
私たちの社会や文化はどのように発展していくのでしょうか？
because if you cut in from the other side
なぜなら、反対側から割り込むと
The reason why I feel that I should share this matter with you
この件についてあなたと共有する必要があると感じた理由
I think it will fundamentally shape the shake
それが根本的にシェイクを形作ることになると思う
each of us to the other
私たちそれぞれがお互いに
we feel very enthusiastic
私たちはとても熱意を感じています
But from another perspective
しかし、別の観点から見ると
For example, in terms of traffic violations
例えば交通違反で言えば、
What about traffic violations?
交通違反についてはどうですか？
Of course the capabilities of the police are limited.
もちろん警察の能力には限界があります。
So what he's saying now is certainly encouraging.
ですから、彼が今言っていることは確かに励みになります。
Everyone, if the public can take the initiative to report
皆さん、国民が率先して報道していただければ。
Even if there are some
いくつかあったとしても
You still have to share some benefits
まだいくつかの利点を共有する必要があります
Then everyone should also know
それならみんなも知ってるはず
Some people don't talk about survival because of this.
このため、生存について話さない人もいます。
At least as a side job.
少なくとも副業としては。
What about this situation, everyone?
皆さん、この状況はどうですか？
we continue to encourage
私たちは励まし続けます
if you continue
続ければ
trust between people
人と人との間の信頼
between people
人と人との間
What about this kind of interaction?
このようなやりとりはどうでしょうか？
Is it built on this whistle blowing culture?
この内部告発文化に基づいて構築されているのでしょうか？
whistleblower culture
内部告発者の文化
is it good or not
それは良いことですか？
This is something we should really think about
これは私たちが本当に考えるべきことです
Then he will talk today
それから彼は今日話します
Actually, you can't do this well
実際には、これをうまく行うことはできません
When you want the people to come out instead
代わりに人に出てきてもらいたいとき
Actually you should think about two things
実際には 2 つのことを考慮する必要があります
The first is the question of the capacity of the government
一つ目は政府の能力の問題です
you are becoming incompetent
あなたは無能になりつつある
The second question to consider is that
考慮すべき 2 番目の質問は、
I don't even know whether the general public should be allowed to
一般人に許可していいのかどうかも分からない
know to abide by the law
法律を遵守することを知っている
minimum traffic rules
最低限の交通ルール
or a bare minimum
または最低限の
As a result, we don't use this to come today
結果的に、今日はこれを使用しません
Instead, through what?
代わりに、何を介して?
by reporting
報告することで
and then through punishment
そして罰を通して
then to strengthen
それから強化するために
It's you who violated me today
今日私を犯したのはあなたです
anytime anywhere
いつでもどこでも
sorry
ごめん
you anytime, anywhere
いつでもどこでもあなた
you pay attention to what's around you
あなたは周りのものに注意を払います
i obviously mean
私は明らかに意味します
Be careful, the spies are by your side
気をつけてください、スパイがあなたの側にいます
change today
今日変える
Be careful and resolute is by your side
用心深く、毅然とした態度があなたのそばにあります
In that case, actually
その場合、実は
On the other hand
一方で
Wait a minute, I'll tell you about it at the beginning
ちょっと待ってください、最初に説明します
this will follow
これは続きます
Some developments in the kind of privacy that we are talking about today
私たちが今日話しているようなプライバシーに関するいくつかの進展
It is related to some developments in the information society
それは情報社会の発展と関係がある
Let's leave a little foreshadowing first
最初に少し伏線を残しておこう
that is
あれは
such a culture
そのような文化
In fact, he will speak slowly
実際、彼はゆっくりと話します
human interaction
人的交流
What kind of relationship would result in
どのような関係が生まれるのか
or what one looks like
またはどのように見えるか
interactive relationship
インタラクティブな関係
Then this situation
この状況が
It may be that we will spend a little more time and come back to talk to you
もしかしたら、もう少し時間をかけて、後でまたお話しすることになるかもしれません。
Let me take a moment now to tell you what the right to privacy is
ここで少し時間をとって、プライバシーの権利とは何かについて説明したいと思います
Maybe the word here might become a comparison
もしかしたらここでの言葉は例えになるかもしれない
not very interesting
あまり面白くない
Because he was entered into the legal challenge
彼は法的異議申し立てを受けていたため、
privacy is important
プライバシーは重要です
Privacy is what we just talked about
プライバシーについては今お話ししたとおりです
Maybe something I don't want others to know
もしかしたら他人には知られたくないことかもしれない
personal facts
個人的な事実
or the one i should
または私がすべきもの
let me have a space alone
一人の空間を与えてください
Have privacy and space
プライバシーとスペースを確保
but if today
でも今日だったら
don't have a stake
利害関係がありません
no legal right
法的権利がない
If the legal system guarantees
法制度が保証するなら
maybe this privacy
おそらくこれはプライバシーです
it will be violated
それは違反されるだろう
so privacy
だからプライバシー
designed words
デザインされた言葉
Mainly to protect personal privacy
主に個人のプライバシーを保護するため
but
しかし
what we want to tell you
私たちがあなたに伝えたいこと
Privacy words in the modern sense of privacy
現代のプライバシーの意味でのプライバシーの言葉
In fact, at the end of the 19th century
実は19世紀末に
just started like this
このように始まったばかりです
modern concept of privacy
プライバシーの現代の概念
That
それか
earliest now present words
現在最も古い言葉
in academia
学術界で
At least in academia
少なくとも学術界では
When it comes to modern privacy
現代のプライバシーに関しては
the establishment of a system
制度の確立
was started in 1890
1890年に開始されました
words from 1890
1890年の言葉
these two lawyers
この二人の弁護士
professional lawyer at the time
当時のプロの弁護士
Both work in Boston
二人ともボストンで働いています
This Samuel Warren
このサミュエル・ウォーレン
Louis Brandeis
ルイ・ブランダイスと
what they wrote
彼らが書いたこと
Then this article is published in Hoverloo Review
その後、この記事は Hoverloo Review に掲載されました
what is the topic of their writing
彼らは何について書いているのですか
The title they wrote was The Right to Privacy
彼らが書いたタイトルは「プライバシーの権利」でした
The Right to Privacy
プライバシーの権利
Then from 1890 onwards
そして1890年以降
The words of this article gradually become a repeatedly quoted
この記事の言葉は次第に繰り返し引用されるようになる
Then everyone is talking about film and television rights
その後、誰もが映画やテレビの権利について話します
will come back to them in the end
最後には彼らに戻ってくるだろう
Of course, everyone can understand, if they should.
もちろん、理解すべきなら誰でも理解できます。
The formation of a concept is never attributable to
概念の形成は決して次の要因によるものではありません。
Home to these two today
今日はこの二人と一緒にいてね
There must be a gestation period
妊娠期間があるはずだ
Then just this paragraph
じゃあこの段落だけ
The words of the two of them caught one eye.
二人の言葉が目に留まった。
then it came out
それから出てきた
So anyway
そう、とにかく
let's talk about this article
この記事について話しましょう
That
それか
Brandeis is a very important
ブランダイスはとても重要です
what about these two
この二人はどうですか
That was at Hoverloo School
それはホバールー学校でした
If you read books, you are bedmates
本を読んでいる人はベッドメイトです
First place Second place
1位 2位
then work at the same time
それから同時に仕事をする
he is very rich
彼はとてもお金持ちです
he is jewish
彼はユダヤ人です
What about Brandice, who later became very famous
後に非常に有名になったブランディスはどうですか
It's not just this article
この記事だけじゃないよ
It's that he later became a justice of the United States Supreme Court.
それは、彼が後にアメリカ合衆国最高裁判所の判事になったことです。
justice
正義
become very important
とても重要になる
right to privacy
プライバシーの権利
we'll talk beyond him
彼のことを超えて話しましょう
The words in Free Speech Studies will also talk about him
『言論の自由研究』の言葉も彼について語るだろう
Then we have to pay attention to the social background at that time
そこで注目すべきは当時の社会背景です。
sorry
ごめん
I have a bad throat recently
最近喉の調子が悪いです
I'm worried that there will be no sound after a while
しばらくすると音が出なくなるのが心配
Everyone noticed that he was a
誰もが彼が
From an agricultural society to an industrial society
農業社会から工業社会へ
what is he doing
彼は何をしているの
Then he is an immigrant society
それから彼は移民社会です
Everyone, think about your childhood
皆さん、自分の子供時代を思い出してください
or as a child
または子供の頃
Do you all use the same childhood as us?
皆さんも私たちと同じ子供時代を過ごしていますか？
When I was a child, I grew up as the head of the dependent village
子供の頃、私は依存する村の長として育ちました
I don't know if you guys are from the general
皆さんが一般の方かどうかは分かりませんが、
Compare
比較
Compare relatives and friends together
親戚や友人を一緒に比較する
The so-called rural society
いわゆる田舎社会
What about that kind of society?
そういう社会はどうでしょうか？
What about him because of emotions
感情のせいで彼はどうなるのか
Everyone, what happened to my house?
皆さん、私の家はどうなりましたか？
compare soon
すぐに比較してください
Of course, the partition wall is also poor in sound insulation.
もちろん、隔壁も遮音性は悪いです。
On the other hand, of course
その一方で、もちろん
Interacting with each other is also very weak
相互作用も非常に弱いです
different from now
今とは違う
you can think about it
それについて考えることができます
a society like that
そんな社会
In a village where I live
私の住んでいる村で
or live in a town
あるいは町に住んでいる
or live in a place
またはその場所に住んでいます
If something happens to my house
もし私の家に何かあったら
everyone around knows
周りの誰もが知っています
Then what kind of Privacy is there at that time?
ではそのときのプライバシーとはどのようなものなのでしょうか？
At that time Privacy may
その際、プライバシーは
No
いいえ
when will he
彼はいつになりますか
Becoming a Privacy may be the conclusion of living with strangers
プライバシーを守ることは、見知らぬ人たちと暮らすことの結論かもしれない
What about this era?
この時代はどうでしょうか？
he might be like this for a reason
彼がこうなったのには理由があるのか​​もしれない
They come out like this because of industrialization
工業化のせいでこうなった
It's all melted
全部溶けてしまった
what about your thoughtful person
あなたの思慮深い人はどうですか
what is no more
もう何がないのか
Your former uncle
あなたの元叔父さん
or auntie
またはおばちゃん
or these relatives and friends
またはこれらの親戚や友人
We've been used to it since childhood
私たちは子供の頃からそれに慣れています
He should know what happened in my house
彼は私の家で何が起こったのか知っているはずです
So we're now at a
それで、私たちは今、
is an unfamiliar environment
慣れない環境です
strangers around
周りの見知らぬ人
So what about the words between strangers?
では、見知らぬ人同士の言葉はどうなるのでしょうか？
don't have that kind of trust
そんな信頼はありません
what happened to me
何が起こったんだ
he talks casually
彼はカジュアルに話します
misunderstood by others
誤解されました
But what if today
しかし、今日だったらどうでしょうか
I'm like the village I grew up in
私は自分が育った国に似ています
A place like this is all about me
このような場所は私のすべてです
people who know me
私を知っている人たち
what happened to me
何が起こったんだ
at least they won't misread me
少なくとも彼らは私を誤解しないでしょう
So I'm going to say one thing here
だからここで一つ言っておきます
Someone will talk about what diet is
誰かがダイエットとは何かについて話すでしょう
Why should the right to food be protected?
なぜ食料への権利が保護されなければならないのでしょうか?
Someone cut in from this angle
誰かがこの角度から切り込んできた
cut it in
それを切り込みます
that is
あれは
because of it
それのせいで
Afraid that others will misinterpret it
他人が誤解するのが怖い
you get these messages
これらのメッセージを受け取ります
Then your message isn't enough
それならあなたのメッセージだけでは十分ではありません
On the other hand
一方で
You told him other than this message
あなたは彼にこのメッセージ以外のことを伝えました
do you know anything else about him
彼について他に何か知っていますか
You do not get it
わかりません
As a result, you interpret it like this
その結果、こう解釈します
so he is also afraid
だから彼も怖がっている
So some people think that
だからこう思う人もいる
Fear of being misunderstood by others
他人に誤解されるのではないかという恐怖
so someone said
それで誰かが言いました
This is an alternative view on protecting the right to privacy
これはプライバシーの権利の保護に関する別の見解です
But that point of view is relatively
しかし、その視点は相対的に
It was only proposed after modern times
近代以降に提唱されたものである
in the middle of communication
コミュニケーションの途中で
no one talks about this
誰もこれについて話さない
But I think he is worth it
でも彼にはそれだけの価値があると思う
By the way, I can share with you
ちなみに、シェアさせていただきます
what is the second one
2番目のものは何ですか
The second is technology
2つ目はテクノロジーです
The technology at that time was called photography
当時の技術は写真と呼ばれていました
Now what are you guys talking about?
さて、あなたたちは何について話しているのですか？
But back then the technology of photography was amazing
でも当時の写真技術はすごかった
because it was from that time
当時からあったから
need your tripod
三脚が必要です
then hit that
それからそれを打ちます
and then what
それから何かになる
He can take it with him
彼はそれを持ち運べる
But at that time, the light bulb was
でも当時の電球は
Throw away when you're done, Throw away when you're done
終わったら捨てる、終わったら捨てる
But anyway, he was a breakthrough
しかしとにかく、彼は画期的な人物だった
That is, he is very convenient. He is a portable
つまり、彼はとても便利です。
moodable he is a mobile
不機嫌そうな彼は携帯電話です
So what if this is the case, everyone?
では、皆さん、そうなったらどうしますか？
The front Warran between the two
両者の間の正面ワラン
He just him because his family is very rich
彼の家族はとても裕福なので、彼は彼だけです
What about his wife?
彼の妻はどうですか？
I also told the wife of the president at the time
当時の社長夫人にも言いました
It's also a boudoir
ここも私室です
Still a bestie, should be a bestie
まだ親友だ、親友であるべきだ
not boudoir
私室ではありません
They're supposed to be best friends, so they're actually one.
彼らは親友であるはずなので、実際には親友です。
In terms of politics, everyone is satisfied
政治に関しては誰もが満足している
I think it's number one
1番だと思うよ
So what happened to his house?
それで彼の家はどうなったのでしょうか？
The newspapers at that time published every episode
当時の新聞には毎話掲載されていた
So actually I should tell you one more thing
それで、実はもう一つ言っておきたいのですが、
New technologies other than these three
この3つ以外の新技術
Information Technology In addition to this modeling technology
情報技術 このモデリング技術に加えて
Another new technology is newspapers
もう一つの新しいテクノロジーは新聞です
Newspapers at the time
当時の新聞
I ignored it here
ここでは無視しました
So that newspaper at that time from the 19th century
それで、19世紀の当時の新聞は
start slowly
ゆっくり始めます
If it develops to that time, he will start to come out halfway.
そこまで発展すると中途半端に出てくるようになる。
At that time, of course newspapers also competed with each other.
もちろん当時は新聞社も競争していた。
he needs this too
彼にもこれが必要です
these businesses
これらのビジネス
these advertisements to maintain his operations
これらの広告は彼の事業を維持するためのものです
i think these words i'm not saying
これらの言葉は私が言っていないと思います
use him to speak now
今すぐ彼を使って話してください
Think about it, when did he cause
考えてみてください、彼はいつ引き起こしたのですか
Proposing such a concept
そんなコンセプトを提案
What is said today, what is said in our current society
今日何が言われているか、現在の社会で何が言われているか
In fact, he made some transformations. In the middle of this transformation,
実際、彼はいくつかの変化を遂げました。
In fact, he should change those concepts a bit.
実際、彼はそれらの概念を少し変える必要があります。
Well, I'm just here to tell you about this matter.
さて、私はこの件についてお話しするためにここに来ただけです。
so we're going to mention this
それでこれについて言及します
other than this thing
この事以外に
I write a lot of things that don't need to be said
言わなくてもいいことたくさん書いてます
I'm just talking to you guys
私はただあなたたちと話しているだけです
Why do they bring these things up
なぜ彼らはこうしたことを持ち出すのか
then speak to them
それから彼らに話しかけてください
words in their most original sense
最も本来の意味での言葉
They think it means don't get fucked
彼らはそれが性行為をするなという意味だと思っている
just don't come and leave me alone
ただ来て私を一人にしないでください
leave me alone
私をほっといて
That
それか
After starting here
ここから始めてから
They were proposed in 1890
それらは 1890 年に提案されました
Afterwards, these things in the United States at that time
その後、当時のアメリカではこんなことが
judicial
司法
or the word of congress
または議会の言葉
not too serious
あまり深刻ではない
By 1901, there was even a case in the state of New York
1901年までにニューヨーク州でも事件が発生した
In that case, a flour mill used a
その場合、製粉工場では
Woman taking his picture as his without the woman's consent
女性の同意なしに彼の写真を自分のものとして撮影する女性
advertise
宣伝する
put it on the flour sack
小麦粉の袋の上に置きます
Then what this woman said, I feel like talking about him
それからこの女性が言ったこと、私は彼のことを話したい気分です
His privacy was violated, sue this New York state
彼のプライバシーは侵害された、ニューヨーク州を訴える
The state courts did not win the state courts, I think
州裁判所は州裁判所で勝訴しなかったと思います
This is an invasion of his privacy
これは彼のプライバシーの侵害です
what about when you come out
出てきたらどうですか？
Many residents of the New York state who died felt that what to say
亡くなったニューヨーク州の住民の多くは、何と言えばよいのか、と感じていた。
It's okay to do such a thing, but you're not a New York state citizen.
そのようなことをするのは問題ありませんが、あなたはニューヨーク州の住民ではありません。
Actually the New York Times
実はニューヨークタイムズ
This is why the newspapers at that time were very important. The newspapers talked about it from the very beginning
だからこそ、当時の新聞は非常に重要であり、新聞は最初からそのことを取り上げていました。
Can it be like this? After this, it will cause everyone
このままでいいの? この後みんなに迷惑がかかるよ
In the field of linguistics, in the field of intellectuals, in the field of social management
言語学の分野で、知識人の分野で、社会経営の分野で
take things like this very seriously
このようなことを非常に真剣に受け止めてください
So, the New York State Congress will pass legislation
それで、ニューヨーク州議会は法案を可決するでしょう
So his earliest legislation
それで彼の最初の法案は
He puts a privacy right like this
彼はプライバシーの権利をこのように定めています
the privacy they want to assert
彼らが主張したいプライバシー
the way he passed the legislation
彼が法案を通過させた方法
into their torts
彼らの不法行為に
Then the development will be very fast
そうすれば開発は非常に早くなります
words developed later
後から発展した言葉
Every state is different
それぞれの州は異なります
words in some states
一部の州の言葉
He speaks straight to the court
彼は法廷で率直に語る
Just use the way of Conmannuo directly
コンマヌオのやり方を使えばいい
Because of Facomano's way
ファコマーノのやり方のせいで
directly into a judgment precedent
直接判例に反映する
other states
他の州
He made it a state law
彼はそれを州法にした
Then in 1960
それから1960年に
in 1960
1960年に
this
これ
Burkeley Low School's then
当時のバークレー低学校
The dean of Burkeley Low School in the United States
米国バークレー低等学校の校長
CalledWilliam Prosser
ウィリアム・プロッサーと呼ばれる
Words from William Prosser
ウィリアム・プロッサーの言葉
he put this
彼はこれを置きました
from 1960
1960年から
Between 1890 and 1960
1890 年から 1960 年の間
The court ruled that he should consult with him
裁判所は彼に相談するべきだとの判決を下した
after the consultation
相談の後
He just said what our American society says
彼は私たちのアメリカ社会が言っていることを言っただけです
For words like invasion of privacy
プライバシーの侵害などの言葉について
The four types of privacy violations
プライバシー侵害の 4 つのタイプ
he summed him up
彼は彼を要約した
Then let me just say it here.
じゃあ、ここで言わせてください。
This Warren proposed to Brandeis
このウォーレンがブランダイスにプロポーズした
When the right to privacy
プライバシーの権利があるとき
he is not created out of nothing
彼は何もないところから創造されたわけではありません
what is he actually
彼は実際何ですか
he also said
彼も言いました
I take all past court decisions
私は過去のすべての裁判所の判決を受け入れます
related to these
これらに関連した
I think what I'm trying to bring up
私が何を持ち出そうとしているのかを考えると、
the right to privacy
プライバシーの権利
about these judgments
これらの判決について
he also found him
彼も彼を見つけた
He is through the experience of being
彼は、という経験を経ています。
then he put him
それから彼は彼を置きました
Analysis after kneeling
ひざまずいた後の分析
and then sum it up
そしてそれを要約します
others did not see he saw
他の人は見ていなかった、彼は見た
That 1960's
あの1960年代
What about Professor Proser?
プロッサー教授はどうでしょうか？
He did the same
彼も同じことをした
same way
同じ方法
also used the past
過去も使った
That is, from 1890 to 1960
つまり、1890 年から 1960 年まで
Judgment of the Intermediate Court
中級裁判所の判決
he summed him up
彼は彼を要約した
So they basically say
つまり彼らは基本的にこう言うのです
not they created
彼らが作ったわけではない
they just take what has happened
彼らは起こったことをただ受け止めるだけだ
he summed him up
彼は彼を要約した
so relatively
とても比較的
So what about the words?
では、言葉についてはどうでしょうか？
The creation of your academics is sometimes quite difficult to talk about
学問の創造について話すのは非常に難しい場合があります
this is your unfamiliarity
これはあなたの奇妙な意見です
if he already exists
彼がすでに存在する場合
so that others do not see
他人に見られないように
I point you out
私はあなたを指摘します
In fact, he already exists there
実際、彼はすでにそこに存在しています
He's actually quite easy to move around.
彼は実際に動き回るのがとても簡単です。
So they came up with these
そこで彼らはこれらを思いつきました
This type of infringement of film and television rights
この種の映画およびテレビの権利侵害
or infringement of the type of infringement of film and television rights
または映画およびテレビの権利侵害に類する侵害
In fact, it has affected the development of related infringements in the world.
実際、それは世界中で関連する侵害の発展に影響を与えています。
Taiwan is particularly affected by this
台湾は特にこの影響を受ける
What about the impact here?
ここでの影響はどうでしょうか？
Of course mainly because
もちろん主な理由は
In addition to the previous piece we just talked about
先ほどお話しした前回の作品に加えて、
That piece is talking
あの作品は話している
From the right of secrets to the right of film and television
秘密の権利から映画とテレビの権利へ
at the turning point in the middle
中盤の折り返し地点で
A lot of discussions there are actually talking about this thing.
そこでは実際にこのことについて多くの議論が行われています。
will talk about you can watch when
いつ視聴できるかについて話します
America they have developed
彼らが発展させたアメリカ
A so-called infringement of film and television rights
いわゆる映画やテレビの権利の侵害
So that's what they're talking about
それが彼らが話していることなのです
What about Germany's weakness?
ドイツの弱さについてはどうですか？
they are talking
彼らは話している
Infringement
侵害
Tell them the right to secrecy
彼らに秘密保持の権利を伝えてください
Later words slowly developed to the present words come in
その後の言葉がゆっくりと発展して現在の言葉になった
To come in is to officially become
入るということは正式になるということです
But everyone should know that this is officially becoming
しかし、これが正式に行われることになることを誰もが知っておくべきです。
from Taiwan
台湾から
law
法律
then it becomes
そうすると、こうなります
It's us
それは私たちです
If someone violates my privacy, I can claim
誰かが私のプライバシーを侵害した場合、私は請求できます
What about infringement
侵害についてはどうですか
is going to
しようとしている
we are at
私たちは〜にて
Although we are talking about the revision of the civil law very early, we have been talking about it since the Republic of China in 1970
私たちは民法改正について非常に早い時期に話し合っていますが、中華民国では1970年から民法改正について話し合っています。
Civil Law Amendment
民法修正
But the real civil law amendment
しかし、実際の民法改正は、
is going to
しようとしている
Only implemented in 1990
1990年にのみ実装された
That is in our general principles of civil law
それは民法の一般原則にあります
195 he corrected it
第195条 彼はそれを訂正した
so
それで
It's funny here, at least when I was a student
ここは面白いよ、少なくとも私が学生だった頃は
when i was a student
私が学生だったとき
There are many cases of well-known cases
有名な事例も多数あります
Some say it's a violation of privacy
プライバシーの侵害だと言う人もいる
So it should be an invasion of privacy
だからプライバシーの侵害になるはずだ
but sorry
でもごめんなさい
Because it's an invasion of privacy, you should go and read the Civil Code.
プライバシーの侵害なので民法を読んだほうがいいでしょう。
Inside, Article 195 talks about invasion of privacy
内部では、第 195 条はプライバシーの侵害について述べています
infringe on this
これを侵害する
If you can ask for the right to be spiritually majestic
精神的に荘厳になる権利を求めることができるなら
does not include privacy
プライバシーは含まれません
he has reputation health body reputation health these
彼は健康な体という評判を持っています。
However, it does not include the so-called
ただし、いわゆるものは含まれません。
privacy
プライバシー
so sorry
ごめんなさい
he can't ask
彼は尋ねることができない
Compensation for damage
所害賠償
At that time, apart from the privacy controversy, another
当時、プライバシーに関する論争とは別に、別の論争があった。
called a quarrel
喧嘩と呼ばれた
At that time, there were many such sexual assault cases in Taiwanese society.
当時、台湾社会ではこうした性暴力事件が多発していた。
What to do if you are assaulted in a sexual assault case
性的暴行事件で暴行を受けた場合はどうすればよいか
So at that time, the words used to violate the body
だからあの時、身体を犯した言葉は
come here with your body
体を持ってここに来てください
What about privacy?
プライバシーについてはどうですか?
words of some courts
一部の裁判所の言葉
They accept the honor
彼らはその名誉を受け入れます
Came here with damage to his reputation because he couldn't find anyone who could use his privacy to claim damages
自分のプライバシーを利用して損害賠償を請求できる人が見つからなかったため、名誉を傷つけられてここに来た
So let me tell you by the way
それで、ちなみに教えてください
Then this is coming officially
それから、これは正式に来ます
After the civil law was amended we have
民法が改正されてからは、
What about other than this film and television rights?
この映画以外のテレビ放映権はどうなるのでしょうか？
if we look
見てみたら
is later continued to develop
その後も開発が続けられている
These four types of infringement of film and television rights may wait a minute, maybe I will follow along and talk to you about that.
映画およびテレビの権利のこれら 4 つのタイプの侵害については、もう少し待って、後でお話しできるかもしれません。
Development of Information Technology
情報技術の発展
By the way, I'll talk to you guys again
ところで、またお話しますね
The development of film and television rights, in addition to infringement
侵害に加えて、映画およびテレビの権利の開発
It's civil, it's between us private and private
それは民事であり、私たちと私たちの間の問題です
if we are here
私たちがここにいるなら
between private and private if my
私の場合はプライベートとプライベートの間で
If my video is infringed on by others, I can come and request
私のビデオが他人に侵害されている場合は、申し立てに行くことができます
This damage is very
このダメージは非常に大きい
On the other hand, you can understand that
その一方で、次のことも理解できます
If he is that important, is there any criminal case other than private through civil
彼がそんなに重要なら、民事から民事以外に刑事事件はありますか？
In the middle of a criminal case, we can also later
刑事事件の最中でも、後からでもできる
Seeing that there is crime of harm prevention secret
秘密の犯罪
The most typical one is
最も典型的なものは、
Because real hole photography has come out
リアルホール写真が出てきたので
Words to prevent pore photography after it has come out
出てしまった後の毛穴撮影を防ぐための言葉
cause a lot of things like this
その結果、このようなことがたくさん起こります
I was in a private space
プライベートな空間にいた
I don't want others to know
他人に知られたくない
It turns out that you used this porosity camera to invade
この多孔性カメラを使って侵入したことが判明
so soon after
その後すぐに
Once it is revised in the criminal law, it will be over soon.
刑法改正されればすぐに終わるだろう。
Because the social groups at that time felt that
当時の社会集団は次のように感じていたからです。
how can it be like this
どうしてこんなことになるんだろう
So we have both civil law and criminal law
つまり、民法と刑法が両方あるのです
What about later?
後はどうですか？
Actually faster
実際はもっと速い
In addition to civil law and criminal law
民法や刑法だけでなく、
It is faster development in Taiwan
台湾の方が開発が早い
He is upside down with America
彼はアメリカとは逆さまだ
It's the other way around with Europe
ヨーロッパとは逆だよ
It is because our administrative regulations existed earlier
それは、我が国の行政法規が比較的早くから存在していたためです。
In the words of our administrative regulations
私たちの管理規定の言葉によれば、
at least since 1988
少なくとも1988年以降は
or before 1989
または1989年以前
We should have some regulations
何らかの規制を設けるべきだ
he will come
彼が来ます
it will be regulated
それは規制されるだろう
You can't invade someone's special identity
誰かの特別なアイデンティティを侵害することはできません
human his privacy
人間のプライバシー
So we can see several conditions
したがって、いくつかの条件がわかります
A few words from this section on privacy protection
プライバシー保護に関するこのセクションからの一言
The first thing we saw was to start from the act of clearing up rights in civil law
私たちが最初に見たのは、民法上の権利を整理することから始まるということでした
Then, if this is the case, if it is the development of the United States
そうすると、これが後々、アメリカの発展だとしたら。
He later arrived in the 1960s
彼はその後 1960 年代に到着しました
started another wave
別の波が始まった
Except we just talked about the 1960s
先ほど 1960 年代の話をしたことを除いて
Professor Proser's words, he summed up the behavior of clearing power
プロサー教授の言葉、彼は浄化力の振る舞いを要約しました
Note also that in the 1960s and 1970s
1960 年代と 1970 年代にも注目してください。
In the middle, the computerization at that time
途中、当時の電子化
he also showed up
彼も現れた
So when computerization comes
それで、コンピュータ化が来ると、
make American society, those they start to worry about
彼らが心配し始めるアメリカ社会
Personal information, will it be the result of computerization?
個人情報、電子化の結果でしょうか？
he was violated
彼は犯された
So they started another wave a new one
それで彼らは新たな波を始めた
A direction to protect the right to privacy through legislation
法律を通じてプライバシーの権利を保護する方向
Then this area is actually in the United States and Europe
そうするとこの地域は実はアメリカやヨーロッパにあるんです
Maybe they were more advanced then
たぶん彼らは当時より進んでいた
So it's weird what I was talking about
だから、私が話していることは奇妙です
Why after the 1970s
なぜ1970年代以降なのか
The word our photographer is positioned
私たちの写真家が位置づける言葉
Is that what the world cared about at the time?
当時世界はそれを重視していましたか？
new cinematographer concept
新しい撮影監督のコンセプト
When a new photographer invades
新しいカメラマンが侵入したとき
some fads are related
いくつかの流行は関連しています
Since the late 1960s and into the 1970s
1960 年代後半から 1970 年代にかけて
The most discussed part in the middle is about the computerization of personal data
真ん中の最も議論されている部分は、個人データの電子化についてです。
If personal data is computerized
個人データが電子化されている場合
They found out that the words
彼らは、この場合の言葉が
Simply through civil tort is not enough
単に民事上の不法行為だけでは十分ではない
because what is that
それは何ですか？
between private and private
プライベートとプライベートの間で
Today is the country to invade me
今日は私を侵略する国です
computerization of the country
国の情報化
Then he came to collect a lot of statistics
それから彼はたくさんの統計を集めに来ました
Census Statistics
国勢調査統計
How can these things be replaced?
これらのものはどのように置き換えることができますか?
So they started to legislate
そこで彼らは立法を始めた
to do this
これをする
Of course, the most famous and typical one is the protection of personal data.
もちろん、最も有名で典型的なものは個人データの保護です。
So after the 70s words
つまり、70年代以降の言葉
new wave
ニューウェーブ
In addition to infringement, another wave of words
侵害に加えて、新たな言葉の波
It's Personal Therapy Protection, and it's been around since then.
それは個人療法保護であり、それ以来存在しています。
just like that
まさにそのように
That
それか
What about Taiwan?
台湾はどうですか？
Taiwan
台湾
Our development just reversed
私たちの発展はちょうど逆転した
if pure if pure
純粋なら純粋なら
From that legal title
その法文から
In this way, our privacy protection
このようにして、私たちのプライバシー保護は、
we may be upside down
私たちは逆さまかもしれない
We are first prescribed by law
私たちはまず法律で定められています
Some provisions of administrative law
行政法の一部の規定
like i just talked about
先ほど話したように
words from 1989
1989年の言葉
Possibly in banking law
おそらく銀行法で
words in banking law
銀行法の言葉
for bank customers
銀行の顧客向け
His personal financial information
彼の個人的な財務情報
should be maintained
維持する必要があります
that privacy
そのプライバシー
What if we come again?
また来たらどうしますか？
is typical
典型的です
Computer Processing Personal Therapy Protection Act
コンピュータ処理個人療法保護法
Words of the Computerized Personal Therapy Protection Act
コンピュータ化された個人療法保護法の文言
before what
何の前に
amendments prior to civil law
民法以前の改正
What about the reason?
理由はどうですか？
There may be other reasons behind
他の理由が背後にある可能性があります
Computer Processing Personal Therapy Protection Act
コンピュータ処理個人療法保護法
The reason why I asked quickly was because
急いで聞いてみた理由は、
At that time, Taiwan hoped to become an Asia-Pacific operation
当時、台湾はアジア太平洋地域の拠点となることを望んでいた
Operations Center
オペレーションセンター
In order to become the Asia-Pacific operations center
アジア太平洋オペレーションセンターを目指して
to know that means I need to accept
それを知るには受け入れる必要があるということ
If we wish to put
置きたい場合は
Other companies that have become multinational
その他の多国籍企業
Ability to set up in Taiwan
台湾での設立能力
set up his Asia-Pacific
アジア太平洋地域を設立する
If the head office is located in Taiwan
本社が台湾にある場合
then these companies
それからこれらの企業
A profile at some other company should be able to
他の会社のプロフィールでは、次のことができるはずです。
Find a way to come to Taiwan
台湾に来る方法を探す
Taiwan also has to find a way
台湾も解決策を見つけなければならない
Relevant transaction information should also be found out
関連する取引情報も確認する必要があります
if you're going to be like this
あなたがこうなるなら
but noticed
しかし気づいた
what we're talking about is saying
私たちが話していることは言っていることです
Because of personal data protection this started
個人情報保護のため、これが始まりました
that in Europe at the time
当時のヨーロッパでは
European Community
欧州共同体
economic community
経済界
predecessor of the european union
欧州連合の前身
words of the predecessor of the european union
欧州連合の前任者の言葉
They also had a word about this matter very early
彼らはまた、この件について非常に早い段階で話がありました
they also care
彼らも気にかけています
So they've made a spec
それで彼らは仕様を作りました
This specification is
この仕様は、
There are regulations on so-called safe harbors
いわゆるセーフハーバーに関する規制がある
It's today
今日です
with these countries in the European Union
欧州連合内のこれらの国々と
sorry eu
ごめんなさい、ユー
that was the european union
それが欧州連合だった
that economy
その経済
We will then
それでは、
Since everyone in the European Union is better than him
欧州連合の誰もが彼より優れているので
Just say it is the European Union
それが欧州連合であると言ってください
If you want to share the economy with me
私と経済を共有したいなら
economic community
経済界
If you want to be an official and do these business dealings
公務員になってこうしたビジネス取引を行いたい場合
It specifically mentioned what this is
これが何であるかを具体的に述べました
My information is from
私の情報源は
countries of the european community
欧州共同体諸国
to another country
他の国へ
this kind
この種
Information flow across borders
国境を越えた情報の流れ
He has one request
彼には一つお願いがある
To stay in that country, that country must have the same norms
その国に留まるには、その国も同じ規範を持たなければなりません
Protection of personal data
保障個人資料
Otherwise, my information will pass
そうしないと私の情報が漏れてしまいます
Therefore, everyone is very clear about this situation. If Taiwan wants to become this
したがって、この状況については誰もが明確に理解しています。
Words from the Asia-Pacific Immigration Center
アジア太平洋移民センターからの言葉
then what becomes
そうするとどうなるのか
I also have to have the same specification
私も同じ仕様にする必要があります
So when we
それで、私たちが
This computer processing personal data protection law will pass soon
このコンピュータ処理個人データ保護法は間もなく可決されます
In fact, if what we are doing is advanced in the legal field, everyone can understand
実は私たちがやっていることが法律分野で進んでいるのであれば、誰でも理解できるのです。
In fact, there were actually a lot of discussions at that time, and other proposals were quickly passed.
実は、当時は本当にたくさんの議論がありまして、他の案もすぐに可決されてしまいました。
So we went through the computer first
そこで最初にコンピューターを調べました
The Personal Data Protection Act and then come back to have amendments to the civil law
個人情報保護法とその後の民法改正
and then put this tort part
そしてこの不法行為の部分を置きます
With film and television rights
映画とテレビの権利付き
So our development
したがって、私たちの開発
no the same
いいえ同じです
But now the word is through these
しかし今、言葉はこれらを通して伝えられています
But there's another, more important part, a more important one
でも、もっと重要な部分がもう一つある、もっと重要な部分がある
partly
部分的に
Is he a de jure right after all we talked about
私たちがすべて話し合った後、彼は法的に適法ですか？
what is
とは
he's a civil tort he's a legal tort
彼は民事上の不法行為だ 彼は法的な不法行為だ
he is personal computer personal data processing personal data protection law
彼はパソコン個人情報処理個人情報保護法です
If the protection of personal data in that personal data
その個人データにおける個人データの保護の場合
If there is also protection of film and television rights, what is he?
映画やテレビの権利も保護されているとしたら、彼は何ですか?
He is also a legal interest
彼は法的利益でもあります
So is he a constitutional right?
では、彼は憲法上の権利を持っているのでしょうか？
If he goes over the Constitution of the Republic of China
もし彼が中華民国憲法を踏み越えるなら
in our constitution
私たちの憲法では
no mention of video rights
ビデオ権利については言及されていない
So what about film rights?
では、映画化権はどうなるのでしょうか？
If you want to realize it well, you can't control it well
うまく実現したければ、うまくコントロールできない
Before the unification of the information society, the time is approaching
情報社会の一元化が迫る時代
So I'm going to enter the information society soon
ということで、これから情報社会に突入します
If our justice is the part of the constitution that protects the right to privacy
私たちの正義がプライバシーの権利を保護する憲法の一部であるなら
through the justice's explanation
裁判官の説明を通じて
So now in our Taiwan
それで今、私たちの台湾では
privacy
プライバシー
the right to privacy it's also a power in the constitution
プライバシーの権利、それは憲法上の権限でもある
we can't jump
私たちはジャンプできない
We Christian Information Society
私たちキリスト教情報協会
Everyone in the information society think about a question
情報社会の中で誰もが問いを考える
Everyone use mobile phones
誰もが携帯電話を使用しています
right
右
Is there anyone without a cell phone?
携帯電話を持っていない人はいますか？
have all
全部持ってる
Everyone uses a mobile phone, so you can understand why you use a mobile phone
誰もが携帯電話を使用しているので、なぜ携帯電話を使用するのか理解できます。
Mobile phones have become an indispensable part of our daily life.
携帯電話は私たちの日常生活に欠かせないものになっています。
very convenient, isn't it
とても便利ですね
I take out my phone when I do something
何かをするときに携帯を取り出す
Maybe there are many people now
もしかしたら今は人が多いのかもしれない
Not looking at me, but looking at me through the phone
私を見ているのではなく、電話越しに私を見ている
If this happens, there are many of you, right?
こうなったら、皆さんも多いのではないでしょうか？
As we said before, many people are obsessed with mobile phones
前にも言ったように、多くの人が携帯電話に夢中になっています。
To what extent are you lost in your phone? Between each other
あなたはどの程度携帯電話に夢中になっていますか?
If you are in the middle of the same crime, if you are chatting with each other
同じ犯罪の最中にある場合、お互いにチャットしている場合
Not talking, but through the phone
話すのではなく電話で
this is very common
これは非常に一般的です
that statement or phenomenon
その発言や現象
It's just describing why the phone it becomes
それは単に、なぜそれが電話になるのかを説明しているだけです
Indispensable in daily life
日常生活に欠かせないもの
But the reason why we become indispensable
でも私たちがなくてはならない存在になる理由
It's because it provides us with too many convenient services, right?
便利なサービスが多すぎるからですよね？
Where am I going today I can't find
今日はどこへ行くのか、見つからない
Where is our original branch, I always Google Map
私たちの元の支店はどこですか、私はいつもグーグルマップを使います
Or map, it just points out Habang
または地図、ハバンを指すだけです
If it wins, I just follow it and get there, right?
勝てば後を追ってそこに着くだけですよね？
That's convenient, but the same
便利だけど同じ
I want to enjoy such a service actually
こんなサービスを実際に楽しみたい
I have to give my information out
私の情報を外に出さなければなりません
come in exchange
代わりに来てください
when i'm going to
いつ行くつもりですか
when I use Google Maps
Googleマップを使いたいとき
What will I definitely use?
絶対に何を使うのでしょうか？
you must provide say
発言権を提供する必要があります
where am i now
私は今どこにいるのか
So this kind of location
ということで、こんなロケーション
Information about personal location
個人の位置情報に関する情報
you have to swap out
交換する必要があります
the same thing too much
同じことが多すぎる
So today's current words
それでは今日の今日の言葉
I'm here to ask you
あなたに尋ねるためにここに来ました
Everyone, do you know
みなさん、知っていますか？
If you are using your mobile phone
携帯電話をご利用の場合
There is so much information exchanged
たくさんの情報交換が行われています
words of information
これらの情報があれば
not just us
私たちだけではありません
And it's anything we just need to surf the Internet on our mobile phone
携帯電話でインターネットを閲覧するのに必要なものはすべて揃っています
That's basically information on mobile phones
基本的には携帯電話の情報です
Then on the other hand
それから一方では
everyone starts today
誰もが今日から始めます
often tell you
よくあなたに言います
words on your phone
携帯電話の言葉
need to be updated
更新する必要がある
The apps inside should also be updated
内部のアプリも更新する必要があります
Much
非常多
I update every day
毎日更新しています
how did he know about you
彼はどうやってあなたのことを知ったのですか
What about updating?
アップデートについてはどうですか？
when i update my app
アプリを更新するとき
Do you want to check out your other stuff by the way?
ところで、他の作品もチェックしてみませんか？
so in many cases
だから多くの場合
when we use mobile phones
携帯電話を使用するとき
In fact, a lot of information has been exchanged
実際、たくさんの情報交換が行われています
then i don't know guys
それならみんな知らないよ
what do you think about this
あなたはこのことについてどう思いますか
I think this information is irrelevant
この情報は関係ないと思います
It doesn't matter if he takes it
彼がそれを受け取るかどうかは問題ではない
Maybe you all think that
もしかしたら皆さんもそう思っているかもしれません
this has nothing to do with my privacy
これは私のプライバシーとは関係ありません
nothing to do with my privacy
私のプライバシーとは何の関係もありません
It may also be that
それもあるかもしれない
Although he has something to do with my privacy
彼は私のプライバシーに関わることがあるのに
but you have a way
でもあなたには方法があります
if not
そうでない場合
How to do it
どうやってするの
Then I will become an off-screen name
そうすれば私は裏名になるでしょう
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
we are curious
私たちは興味があります
In fact, many things today are like this
実際、今日の多くのことはこれに似ています
we just talked about cell phone
ちょうど携帯電話の話をしました
In fact, inside the National Taiwan University campus
実は国立台湾大学のキャンパス内
We are looking inside the original
オリジナルの内部を調べています
I've seen several cameras
何台ものカメラを見てきましたが、
then go out
それから出かける
probably a lot of cameras
おそらくカメラがたくさんあるでしょう
To maintain campus safety
キャンパスの安全を守るために
There are also many cameras
カメラもたくさんあります
In fact, any street
実際、どんな街路でも
You can see the camera when you enter privately
プライベートで入るとカメラが見えます
then we take a taxi
それからタクシーに乗ります
taxi
タクシー
Driving machine
駆動機
Then wherever you go
それならどこに行っても
Everyone is watching us and we are watching others
誰もが私たちを見ています、そして私たちも他の人を見ています
So now the current words
それで今の言葉は
probably into a
おそらく
Big Brother like 1984
1984年のようなビッグ・ブラザー
Watching you all the time, except for the government
政府を除いて、いつもあなたを見守っています
What else is there besides this big brother?
この兄貴以外に何がいるんだ？
And these are our Rolomon
そしてこれが私たちのロロモンです
These little big brothers or little big sisters
この小さなお兄さんまたは小さなお姉さんたち
we are helping big brother
私たちは兄貴を助けています
So now society has become
それで今の社会はこうなっている
enter into a
に入る
people are changing
人々は変わりつつある
Under surveillance, all the people are also there
国民全員が監視下にある
one who watches over others
他人を見守る人
This is monitoring
これはモニタリングです
severance
退職金
In this case, there is actually a risk
この場合、実はリスクがあります
We just said that everyone is
誰もがそうであると先ほど言いました
Report and report
報告と報告
If any
もしあれば
we live in a so-called
私たちはいわゆる
In the era when all the people are being monitored
全国民が監視される時代
Actually what does it mean here?
実際、ここでの意味は何でしょうか？
In fact, it is a discipline function
実際、それは規律機能です
we pass this way
私たちはここを通ります
The most typical statement is
最も典型的な発言は、
benson
ベンソン
This British philosopher Benton invented
イギリスの哲学者ベントンが発明した
the so-called prototype prison theory
いわゆる原型刑務所理論
The words of his archetypal prison theory are
彼の典型的な刑務所理論の言葉は次のとおりです。
He can design this kind of prison called a prototype
彼はプロトタイプと呼ばれるこの種の刑務所を設計できます
He just needs to have a warden in the middle of this prison
この刑務所の真ん中に所長を置く必要があるだけだ
He can see inside every precaution
彼はあらゆる予防策の内側を理解できる
everyone is active
みんながアクティブです
Then don't those in the prevention
では、予防をしている人たちはそうしませんか？
the words of the prisoners
囚人の言葉
he can't see this admin
彼にはこの管理者が見えません
he can see them he can't see him
彼にはそれらが見えます、彼は見えません
And what will he become in the last words?
そして最後の言葉で彼はどうなるのか？
None of this admin needs to exist
この管理者は存在する必要はありません
because of what
何かのせいで
They don't know he can't see
彼らは彼が見えないことを知らない
Are the admins watching them?
管理者は監視してますか？
But he'll take it to mean they're looking at them
でも彼はそれを彼らが見ているという意味だと受け取るだろう
just like today
今日のように
today's words
今日の言葉
I honestly don't know if anyone is watching me
正直、誰かが私を見ているかどうかはわかりません
But I know someone is watching me
でも誰かが私を見ているのはわかっている
That's an unknowable
それは不可知なことだ
What is the most troublesome thing today?
今日一番困ったことは何ですか？
The most troublesome thing is
一番困るのは、
we don't know
私たちは知りません
Information about who we are personally
私たち個人に関する情報
by what kind of person
どのような人によって
By what means does he collect
彼はどのような手段で集めているのか
We don't know where he's stored
彼がどこに保管されているかわかりません
Then how he was used we don't know
その後、彼がどのように使われたかはわかりません
We don't know what the result of his use is.
彼が使用された結果がどうなるかはわかりません。
this is now
これは今です
To be honest, for me to do a research on shadow rights
正直に言うと、影の権利について調査するには
To be honest, I have been talking to foreign scholars
正直に言うと、私は外国の学者と話してきました。
I'm sorry, a lot of things are actually in my imagination
ごめんなさい、実際には私の想像の中でのことがたくさんあります
because we have no data
データがないので
if you do research
研究をすれば
Of course you need to know what reality is
もちろん現実が何であるかを知る必要があります
You don't know reality, that's all you're imagining
あなたは現実を知らない、それがあなたの想像だけです
but what is the reality
しかし現実は何ですか
reality is we don't know
現実は私たちには分かりません
Our profile Says our profile on the Internet
私たちのプロフィール インターネット上の私たちのプロフィールを言います
I don't know if I'm used to it
慣れているかどうかはわかりませんが、
Do you have our information over there? We don't know either.
向こうの私たちの情報を持っていますか? 私たちも知りません。
No matter how our data is used, we don’t know
データがどのように使用されるかはわかりません
Do not know at all
全く分からない
In this case, it is irresistible to care
この場合、気になって仕方がありません。
So today we will follow
ということで今日はフォローさせていただきます
Sorry, I should have said this earlier today.
申し訳ありませんが、今日もっと早くにこれを言うべきでした。
In fact, one important thing is
実際、重要なことは 1 つあります
we have to understand
私たちは理解しなければなりません
The exchange of social information today
今日の社会情報の交換
It is indispensable in our daily life
私たちの日常生活に欠かせないものです
There's really no way around this
これを回避する方法は本当にありません
but
しかし
He should be a norm that must be justified
彼は正当化されるべき規範であるべきだ
reasonable management
合理的な管理
But we don't know what the mechanism is
しかし、そのメカニズムはわかっていません
Thanks
ありがとう
So this is a question we want to talk to you today
今日はこれが皆さんに話したい質問です
Well, we actually have some regulations in the law.
そうですね、実際には法律でいくつかの規制があります。
What about this law? For example, we just talked about the Personal Data Protection Law.
この法律はどうなるかというと、例えば先ほど個人情報保護法の話が出ました。
Or like some legal regulations just mentioned
あるいは、先ほど述べたいくつかの法的規制のように
He actually had a hypothesis
実は彼には仮説があった
because we just talked about privacy
プライバシーについて話したばかりなので
In privacy, there is one thing he calls
プライバシーにおいて、彼が大切にしていることは 1 つあります
I want to be in charge, I want to make my own decisions
主導権を握りたい、自分で決断したい
So, when protecting everyone's privacy through the law through the right to privacy of the law?
では、法律のプライバシーの権利を通じて、法律を通じてすべての人のプライバシーを保護する場合はどうでしょうか？
he has one thing
彼には一つのことがある
It's very important, everyone may have heard it.
とても重要なことなので、誰もが聞いたことがあるかもしれません。
Hidden consent
隠された同意
be informed first
最初に知らされる
Then with your consent
その後、あなたの同意を得て
Then this becomes everything looks legal
そうすれば、これですべてが合法に見えるようになります
access to information
情報へのアクセス
The collection, storage and utilization of this collection
このコレクションの収集、保管および利用
is also true
それも本当です
If you have the consent of the parties
当事者の同意がある場合
ok
Ok
Then we'll look at the consent of the parties.
次に、当事者の同意について見ていきます。
In fact, everyone
実は皆さん、
We agree to so many things without knowing it
私たちは知らず知らずのうちに多くのことに同意してしまう
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Like say you are using your phone today
たとえば、今日電話を使用しているとします
use your computer use your many things
コンピューターを使用して、さまざまなものを使用してください
He always asks if you agree or not
彼はいつもあなたが同意するかどうか尋ねます
can you disagree
同意できますか
if you disagree
同意しない場合
then it's gone
それから消えた
so it's an exchange
それで交換です
One more troublesome thing is to say
もう一つ厄介なことを言うと、
i have no idea what i'm agreeing to
何に同意しているのか分かりません
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Because he said so many terms
彼はたくさんの言葉を言ったから
Turns out we're more fun
僕らはもっと楽しいことがわかった
The contradictory thing is this
矛盾しているのはこれです
that is
あれは
You can't protect consumers
消費者を守れない
You can't speak so clearly
あなたはそんなにはっきりと話すことはできません
As a result, he wanted to speak more clearly and longer
その結果、彼はもっとはっきりと長く話したいと思った
then you don't even want to see
それなら見たくないでしょう
Isn't that right? And a lot of them are weak in principle, weak in principle.
そうじゃないですか? そして彼らの多くは原理的に弱い、原理的に弱いのです。
He thinks about it very carefully
彼はそれについてとても注意深く考えます
But will you watch it?
でも、見ますか？
I'm bored. Maybe your first time will look good.
退屈だよ。初めてはいい感じになるかもしれない。
After reading the first page, there are still so many pages to read. Forget it.
最初のページを読んだ後でも、読まなければならないページはまだたくさんありますが、それは忘れてください。
agree agree agree
同意 同意 同意
Has anyone disagreed?
反対する人はいますか?
If you don't agree, don't use him
同意しないなら彼を利用しないでください
But the troublesome thing is that we have no way today not to use
しかし、厄介なのは、今日ではこれを使わない方法はないということです。
He has become an indispensable part of our daily life, so many of our services are like this
私たちの日常生活に欠かせない存在となっているので、私たちのサービスの多くはこのようなものです
But everyone, you can take your time to see more and more things
でも皆さん、ゆっくりもっといろんなものを見てくださいね
Tell us right now that the internal Fins IoT is coming
内部 Fins IoT が登場することを今すぐ教えてください
Then today's words, the words of data collection
それでは今日の言葉、取材の言葉
He is no longer his collection of data intruding on these things you use
彼はもはや、あなたが使用するこれらのものに侵入する彼のデータのコレクションではありません
Objects are collecting data anytime, anywhere
オブジェクトはいつでもどこでもデータを収集します
The bigger technology behind that
その背後にあるより大きなテクノロジー
Everyone heard big data
誰もがビッグデータを聞いた
Here comes the technology
ここにテクノロジーが登場します
technology, the better the technology
テクノロジー、テクノロジーが優れていればいるほど
Everyone just needs more information
誰もがもっと情報を必要としているだけです
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
then hear it say
それからそれが言うのを聞いてください
Our new AI for you is here
あなたのための新しい AI が登場
so we used to
それで私たちは以前は
We were telling a joke the other day
先日私たちは冗談を言いました
Well, in the future we are actually very convenient
まあ、将来的には本当に便利になります
Because we all have AI in front
私たち全員が AI を目の前にしているからです
So what if I continue with you?
それで、私があなたと続けたらどうなるでしょうか？
Actually we were saying
実は私たちはこう言っていたのです
How do you know that what you make is not written by AI
自分が作ったものが AI によって書かれたものではないことをどうやって知ることができますか
Then another sentence says
それから別の文はこう言います
Then how do you know that what I wrote to you was not written by AI
では、私があなたに書いたものが AI によって書かれたものではないことをどうやって知ることができるのでしょうか
They communicate with each other than directly
直接ではなく相互に通信します
In fact, we are all doing next to
実際、私たちは皆、次のことをしています。
In fact, AI is doing everything for us
実際、AI は私たちのためにあらゆることをやってくれます。
In fact, he may be like this in the future
実は彼も将来こうなるかもしれない
So in this situation
したがって、この状況では
what should we do
私たちは何をすべき
We just talked about the fact
私たちはその事実について話したばかりです
The thing that should matter is a transparent
重要なのは透明性です
Actually we don't need much
実際にはあまり必要ありません
one thing you want is
あなたが欲しいものは一つです
please let us know
お知らせください
you are probably currently
あなたはおそらく現在
what technology do you use
どのようなテクノロジーを使用していますか
What kind of information is being collected from me
私から収集される情報の種類
How do you use this information?
この情報をどのように使用しますか?
what did he do
彼が何をした
Today, maybe we can ask the government like this
今日、私たちは政府にこのように尋ねることができるかもしれません
But the government did not respond
しかし政府は応じなかった
Maybe today, you see, there's no way to respond except the government
おそらく今日は、政府以外に対応する方法はないでしょう
We also want the government to help us fight some
私たちは政府にも、いくつかの戦いを支援してもらいたいと考えています。
These private, these large corporations
これらの民間企業、これらの大企業
In fact, if we look from the other side
実際、反対側から見てみると
In fact, some phenomena can also be seen
実際にこんな現象も見られます
Facebook Google these two big three
Facebook Google この 2 つのビッグ 3
This is a so-called mid-level media service industry in the middle of the Internet
いわゆるインターネットど真ん中の中堅メディアサービス業です
intermediaries
仲介者
In fact, their services are almost in the
実際、彼らのサービスはすでにほぼ完成しています。
in the middle of our daily life
私たちの日常生活の真ん中で
That's what we can see developing in the U.S.
それが米国での発展が見られるものです。
Following the development in Europe, the impact on these two companies
欧州での展開に伴う両社への影響
maybe too same
たぶん同じすぎる
Then we have recently seen a series of words in the United States
そして、最近米国で一連の言葉を目にしました。
they will think that
彼らはそう思うだろう
because they want to maintain a so-called
彼らはいわゆる
The technology of this technology
この技術の技術
or from the Internet
またはインターネットから
Should be a new chart
新しいチャートになるはずです
So these should
したがって、これらは
For the intermediary part, he should be neutral
仲介役としては中立であるべきだ
So speaking neutral means to say
つまり、中立的に話すということは、次のように言うことを意味します
The government basically does not intervene
政府は基本的に介入しない
What about his kind of service?
彼のようなサービスはどうですか？
he will flourish
彼は繁栄するだろう
Then you can think about it
それなら考えてもいいよ
What if today's intermediary service industry
今の仲介サービス業だったらどうなるか
He has a lot of liability
彼には大きな責任がある
he has many legal responsibilities
彼には多くの法的責任がある
He may worry at every turn
彼はことあるごとに心配するかもしれない
What if I will be sued?
訴えられたらどうなりますか？
On the other hand, he told you
一方で、彼はあなたにこう言いました
as long as you don't intervene yourself
自分自身が介入しない限り
don't write it yourself
あなたは自分でそれを書いていません
you don't edit
あなたは編集しません
you don't check
あなたはチェックしません
you are all right
大丈夫
this is in america
ここはアメリカです
But what about today?
しかし今日はどうでしょうか？
you can see europe he's not like that
ヨーロッパはわかるだろう、彼はそんな人ではない
So we can see what the EU says
EUが何を言っているか分かる
he has some cases
彼にはいくつかのケースがある
Even Canada has some cases
カナダでも事例はある
for Facebook or for Google
Facebook または Google の場合
So this is basically thinking
つまり、これは基本的に考えています
what are we looking at
私たちは何を見ているのですか
we see now
今わかります
these other advanced countries
これらの他の先進国
how do they come through
彼らはどのようにしてやって来ますか
what mechanism to protect these
これらを保護するメカニズムは何ですか
General user or consumer
一般ユーザーまたは消費者
Then we can first see that
そうすれば、まず次のことがわかります
there are some strange
いくつか奇妙なことがある
So how does Taiwan go?
さて、台湾はどうなるでしょうか？
Taiwan is a relatively difficult place, we must face the reality
台湾は比較的困難な場所です、私たちは現実を直視しなければなりません
we are small
私たちは小さいです
how much leverage do we have
私たちはどのくらいのレバレッジを持っていますか
If today, I'll go somewhere, I'll deal with one
もし今日どこかに行くなら、私が対処します
An intermediaries of transnational
国境を越えた仲介者
I said you have to conform, if you don’t conform, you can’t do it
従わなければならないと言いましたが、従わないならそれはできません
will he talk to us
彼は私たちに話してくれますか
So this is also some reality, so we all know these realities
これもまた現実なので、私たちは皆、これらの現実を知っています
what should we do
私たちは何をすべき
In fact, this is something we should think about
実際、これは私たちが考えるべきことです
There are actually a lot of words today
今日は本当に言葉が多いです
We just cut this information from the perspective of film and television rights
映画とテレビの権利の観点からこの情報をカットしただけです
When it comes in, everyone will say that I don’t want to circulate information. I don’t want to circulate information.
それが入ってくると、みんなが「情報を流通させたくない、情報を流通させたくない」と言うでしょう。
not that
しないこと
The open circulation of information is a very important aspect of the progress of human civilization.
情報のオープンな流通は、人類文明の進歩にとって非常に重要な側面です。
Base
基礎
you can think about it
それについて考えることができます
If there is a free flow of information, our knowledge exchange and our access to information can promote our
情報の自由な流れがあれば、私たちの知識交換と情報へのアクセスは、私たちの活動を促進することができます。
Knowledge
知識
Let us have a lot of new developments
新たな展開をたくさんしていきましょう
It's all a human being exchanging information with each other.
それはすべて人間がお互いに情報を交換することです。
Say we can't ignore this
これを無視することはできないと言う
But in the free flow of information
しかし、情報の自由な流れの中で
Between the protection of personal privacy
個人のプライバシーの保護の間
we have to have a balance
私たちはバランスを取らなければなりません
If the balance
残高があれば
Today is not about us closing our eyes and covering them
今日は目を閉じて覆うことではありません
If your head is in the sand
頭が砂の中にあるなら
we don't care
私たちは気にしません
it will naturally become good
自然と良くなるよ
In fact, what we see today is that
実際、今日私たちが目にしているのは、
Your government must be very real to face such things
あなたの政府はそのようなことに直面するために非常に現実的である必要があります
that information
その情報
you if you say yes
あなたが「はい」と言うなら
I should develop Big Data today
今日はビッグデータを開発しなければなりません
I want to develop AI
AIを開発したい
I want to develop many, many things
たくさんのことを開発したい
In fact, I have to provide a lot of information
実は、たくさんの情報を提供しなければならないのですが、
I have to collect a lot of information
たくさんの情報を集めなければなりません
I want to develop my business industry
自分のビジネス業界を発展させたい
I also need a lot of information
私もたくさんの情報が必要です
we all know that
我々はすべてそれを知っている
But on the other hand
しかしその一方で、
that person's privacy
その人のプライバシー
personal information
個人情報
Shouldn't it also be properly protected?
それもきちんと守るべきではないでしょうか？
the protection that now provides
現在提供されている保護
Those words are actually what we have to face.
その言葉こそ、実は私たちが向き合わなければならないものなのです。
So I because of time
だから私は時間のせいで
The last thing I want to share with you is
最後に皆さんと共有したいことは、
if we personally
私たち個人であれば
Each of us cares about our personal privacy
私たち一人ひとりが個人のプライバシーを大切にしています
then you really have to care about privacy
それならプライバシーに本当に気を配る必要がある
you have to think about it
それについて考えなければなりません
if you do anything today
今日何かするなら
that with your personal privacy
それはあなたの個人的なプライバシーに関わるものです
is it related
それは関係していますか
On the other hand, of course
その一方で、もちろん
we probably know
私たちはおそらく知っています
words in the middle of modern society
現代社会のど真ん中の言葉
many of our services
私たちのサービスの多くは
Or something we want to use in our daily life
または日常生活で使いたいもの
words of essential things today
今日の大切なことの言葉
It is through the exchange of personal data
それは個人データの交換を通じて行われます
exchanged like this
このように交換しました
there is no way
道はない
On the other hand
一方で
We must also use these words of appeal
私たちもこのような訴えの言葉を使わなければなりません
may make everyone understand
みんなに理解してもらえるかもしれない
You can't just sit there and wait
ただ座って待つことはできない
Because if you just sit there and wait
だって、ただそこに座って待っていたら
If the government does nothing
政府が何もしなければ
Then in this situation
すると、この状況で
Many things are only getting worse
多くのことが悪化の一途をたどっている
And then when you start going in like for example
そして、たとえば、あなたが入り始めると、
you can op out
オプトアウトできます
you can refuse
拒否できます
i terminated
私は終了しました
But here comes the next controversy
しかし、ここで次の論争が起こります
What should I do if the front has already flowed out?
すでにフロントが流れ出てしまった場合はどうすればよいですか？
information our most difficult place
情報 私たちの最も困難な場所
Just when the shadow sealed Kang Sheng
影が康生を封印したその時
We think the hardest part is
私たちが考える最も難しい部分は、
Let's assume
仮定しましょう
i am one i know
私は私が知っている一人です
i love my privacy
私は自分のプライバシーが大好きです
I also know a lot of things
私も色々なことを知っています
But the next thing is
でも次は
Because the current information
現時点での情報なので
the development of a technology
技術開発
we just talked about big data
先ほどビッグデータについて話しました
such a development
そんな展開
It actually becomes a situation
実際にそうなる状況になる
is out of our control
私たちの制御の外にあります
is information
情報です
It data its cumulative effect
その累積効果をデータ化します
original words
オリジナルの言葉
You can see the words in the Personal Data Protection Act
個人情報保護法の文言がわかります
it talks a lot
それはたくさん話します
This is also a worldwide
これも世界共通です
Everyone can only talk
誰もが話すことしかできない
If you want to protect a personal data
個人情報を保護したい場合
Under such circumstances
このような状況下では
there is one thing you can do
あなたにできることが1つあります
if you do this
これをやれば
Let's just assume it's like this
こんな感じだと仮定してみましょう
what's the matter
どうしたの
de-identification
匿名化
We study the words of many colleagues
私たちは多くの同僚の言葉を研究します
What everyone can understand is to say
誰もが理解できることは、
In the personal data protection law
個人情報保護法では
referred to in Article 6
第6条で言及される
Or in 19, 20
あるいは19、20年に
It was mentioned on 19 and 80
19と80で言及されました
he talked about it
彼はそれについて話しました
de-identification
匿名化
He means de-identification
彼は匿名化を意味します
This is actually in the EU
これは実際にはEUにあります
He also talks about de-identification
彼は匿名化についても語っています
You just have to de-identify
匿名化すればいいだけ
Information flow should be no problem
情報の流れは問題ないはず
But he ignored the development of information technology
しかし彼は情報技術の発展を無視した
After de-identification, he can re-identify
匿名化後、再識別できる
That's the problem now
それが今の問題です
What is it in the words of identification?
識別という言葉で言えば何でしょうか？
more information
詳しくは
The easier it is for him to recognize
彼が認識しやすいほど
So re-identification
それで再識別
Originally de-identification
もともと匿名化
Now it's re-identification
現在是re-identification
that on the other hand is
それは一方で
we don't know what to say
私たちは何を言えばいいのか分かりません
Even if we really all know about it
たとえ本当にみんながそれを知っていたとしても
Everything
すべての
If I personally know what went out
私が個人的に何が起こったのかを知っているとしたら
thought about it
それについて考えた
But we don't know the information going out
しかし、外に出ている情報は分かりません
What is the effect of the addition behind him?
彼の背後に追加された効果は何ですか？
this is what we don't know
これは私たちが知らないことです
so many things are
とてもたくさんのことが
we do not know
我々は知りません
we know
私たちは知っています
no way to control
制御する方法がない
Under such circumstances
このような状況下では
what should we do
私たちは何をすべき
we may ask the government
私たちは政府に尋ねるかもしれません
If the government does nothing
政府が何もしなければ
also have problems
問題もあります
So I personally would think that
なので個人的にはそう思います
In fact, the government should deal with this matter
本当は政府がこの問題に取り組むべきだ
then put some
それからいくつか入れてください
such a difficulty
そんな困難
He should discuss it openly
彼はそれについてオープンに話し合うべきだ
Therefore, if we pass legislation
したがって、法案を通過させれば、
At least in the middle of the halls of Congress
少なくとも国会議事堂の真ん中では
he has room for discussion
彼には議論の余地がある
Bundle
バンドル
spread out
広がる
we make choices
私たちは選択をします
What about before this?
この前はどうでしょうか？
can only say
としか言えません
Good luck to everyone
みんな頑張ってね
ok thank you guys i'll stop here for now
わかりました、ありがとう、今回はここでやめておきます
this
これ
make this
これ作って
take a breath in your hand
手の中で息をする
give him a break
彼に休憩を与えてください
this i think we just heard this
これは今聞いたばかりだと思います
Professor Lin has many very enlightening talks
リン教授は非常に啓発的な講演を数多く行っています
That
それか
I find this very interesting
これはとても興味深いと思います
I also think that means
という意味もあると思います
what he talks about you can see this
彼が何を話しているのか、これを見ればわかります
How is modern society different from traditional society?
現代社会は伝統的な社会とどう違うのでしょうか？
What is he talking about about privacy?
彼はプライバシーについて何を話しているのでしょうか?
What do you talk about in traditional society?
伝統的な社会では何を話しますか?
must be fun
楽しいはずだ
Because the first we know that this traditional society follows
なぜなら、この伝統的な社会が次のようなものであることを私たちは初めて知っているからです。
between public and private
パブリックとプライベートの間で
Change
変化
what do you think you can't tell others
他人に言えないことは何だと思いますか
should tell others
他の人に言うべきです
you have nothing to hide like this
このように隠すことは何もありません
It can be seen that the changes in this society are indeed very fast.
この社会の変化は実に早いことがわかります。
Then I think this is called a study of intellectual history
そうすると、これは思想史の研究と呼ばれるものだと思います。
very interesting
とても興味深い
You can look at traditional people's views on public and private
公的および私的に関する伝統的な人々の見解を見ることができます
with us modern
現代の私たちと一緒に
Because of the changes in social technology
社会テクノロジーの変化により
he is very different
彼はとても違う
So while he was talking I was comparing
それで彼が話している間、私は比較していました
How would Song-Ming Neo-Confucians respond to him?
宋明の朱子学者は彼にどう反応するでしょうか？
So I think the person who said this wants to talk about this right to privacy
つまり、これを言った人はプライバシーの権利について話したいのだと思います
very problematic
非常に問題のある
This he becomes you to talk about privacy
これで彼はあなたにプライバシーについて話すようになります
means you must be morally flawed
あなたは道徳的に欠陥があるに違いないことを意味します
so this is fun
だからこれは楽しい
i just heard
今聞いた
This is what you told Zhu Xi and Wang Yangming in ancient times
これはあなたが古代に朱熙と王陽明に語ったものです
You must be a villain
あなたは悪役に違いない
What right do you have to defend your rights?
自分の権利を守るためにはどんな権利があるのでしょうか？
this is even weirder
これはさらに奇妙です
So the society is actually
ですから社会というのは実際のところ、
This has changed a lot
これは大きく変わりました
But now I will leave this time open for you to ask questions
ただし、今回は質問を受け付けるための時間を残しておきます
Then there is an encouragement among us
そうすれば私たちの間で励ましが生まれます
Anyone who asks a question
質問する人は誰でも
We'll send a Scientist magazine
科学雑誌をお送りします
Only those who have questions
ご質問のある方のみ
This is what I was ordered to announce to you just now
これが私がたった今あなたに発表するよう命じられたものです
then we stay
それから私たちはここにいます
You can see it there in a little while
もう少ししたらあそこで見れるよ
this is very beautiful
これはとても美しいです
very good magazine
とても良い雑誌
then i miss everyone
それからみんなに会いたい
Will use the industry to feel expensive
高価だと感じるために業界を利用する
Many of the high-tech technologies that the teacher just talked about
先生が今話された多くのハイテク技術
The helplessness of using electronic products
電化製品を使うことの無力さ
I am
私は
I don't feel anything
何も感じない
because there is no way
方法がないから
But you have observed a phenomenon over the past few years
しかし、あなたは過去数年間にある現象を観察しました
It means you watch any news
それはどんなニュースでも見るということです
any one
誰
news at any time
いつでもニュース
You will see that our news seems to have become one
私たちのニュースが一つになったように見えるでしょう
Surveillance Video News
監視ビデオニュース
That
それか
In the early years and a few years ago, there was a big debate in the society whether to install a lot of monitors
初期の数年前、社会ではモニターをたくさん設置すべきかどうかという大きな議論がありました。
Of course, the reason of the security unit of the police force is that this is a problem of public security.
もちろん、警察の警備隊がいるのは、これは治安の問題だからです。
Human rights can be compromised a bit, basically I can barely accept it.
多少の人権侵害はあるかもしれないが、基本的にはギリギリ許容できる。
brought in
持ち込まれた
after playing on tv
テレビで遊んだ後
Someone may speak next
次に誰かが話すかもしれません
It's almost a mold to operate like this
このように動作するのはほぼ型です
Some things after sacrificing human rights
人権を犠牲にした後のこと
But if you question this phenomenon today
しかし、今日この現象に疑問を抱くなら、
Then they will also say that we have mosaics
そうしたらモザイクがあるとも言われるでしょう
No, we have to cover our faces too.
いいえ、私たちも顔を隠さなければなりません。
Just like what the teacher said just now
今先生がおっしゃった通りです
so-called differentiation
いわゆる差別化
What does the teacher think about this phenomenon?
先生はこの現象についてどう思いますか?
Thanks
ありがとう
In fact, it is useless in the end to say goodbye
実際、別れを告げても結局は無駄だ
Because Xiao Min found you out soon
シャオミンがすぐにあなたを見つけたから
Of course, this phenomenon is actually a
もちろん、この現象は実際には
It is also a last resort
それは最後の手段でもあります
That's called the Great Wall of Electronics
それは電子機器の万里の長城と呼ばれます
That many of our governments, local governments or communities
私たちの政府、地方自治体、コミュニティの多くが
he will feel that we need to restructure
彼は我々が再構築する必要があると感じるだろう
Our Great Wall of Electronics
私たちのエレクトロニクスの万里の長城
That's because they figured out that monitors are basically
それは、モニターは基本的に次のようなものであると彼らが理解したからです。
A very low cost but
非常に低コストですが、
The psychological effect is great
精神的な効果は大きい
as long as he is there
彼がそこにいる限り
For many others, as we just said, he has a disciplinary function.
他の多くの人々にとって、先ほど述べたように、彼は懲戒の役割を果たしています。
You don't know if he has it there
彼がそこにそれを持っているかどうかはわかりません
Is it useful, you don't know if it is really useful
役に立つのか、本当に役に立つのか分からない
On the other hand, I don’t know if anyone
一方、誰かは分かりませんが、
I'm really looking at you and I don't know
本当にあなたを見ているのですが、わかりません
this is a problem
これは問題だ
Well, what you just said actually involved a few things.
さて、あなたが今言ったことには、実際にはいくつかのことが含まれています。
One is to say what we see is to say
1つは、私たちが見ているものを言うことです
there are these monitors everywhere
どこにでもこのモニターがあります
What about these monitors?
これらのモニターはどうですか?
Everyone knows that now with the facial recognition system
今では顔認識システムのおかげで誰もがそれを知っています
basically
基本的
There is probably nowhere for a man to escape
男には逃げ場がないかもしれない
Wherever you go, everyone will know who you are
どこに行っても、誰もがあなたが誰であるかを知るでしょう
that is fast
それは速いです
Because the facial recognition system is better now
今は顔認証システムが良くなったから
That day my assistant showed me the new Economics
その日、私のアシスタントは私に新しい経済学を見せてくれました
He has said that he is not just a facial recognition system
彼は、自分は単なる顔認識システムではないと述べています
He is through technology
彼はテクノロジーを駆使している
He even backtracked and said
彼は後戻りしてこうも言った
if i knew your genes
もしあなたの遺伝子を知っていたら
I also know what you'll look like
私もあなたがどんな表情をするか知っています
Then I heard wow how could this be like this
それから私はすごいことを聞きました、どうしてこれがこんなことになるのですか
it's not that's another thing
それは別のことだ
But that means there's nothing to hide from
でもそれは、隠すものがないことを意味する
what about this
これはどうですか
There is actually something deeper behind that
実はその裏にはもっと深いものがある
Can the media do something like this?
マスコミはこんな事やっていいのか？
of course
もちろん
who gave it to the media
誰がそれをメディアに渡したのか
Of course people are our parties
もちろん人々は私たちの当事者です
Like, for example, we used to have a dispute
たとえば、私たちは昔口論をしていました
it's you
それはあなたです
Let's not talk about the normal one
通常のものについては話さないようにしましょう
you passed through you if we were driving today
もし私たちが今日運転していたら、あなたはあなたを通り過ぎていきました
For driving, we have a driving recorder installed.
運転に関してはドライブレコーダーを設置しております。
What about the driving recorder? When can you use it?
ドライブレコーダーはいつから使えるの？
Use the record in that driving recorder
そのドライブレコーダーの記録を利用する
The truth is, it should be your own car accident.
真実を言えば、それはあなた自身の交通事故であるべきです。
or when there is a flip gain
またはフリップゲインがある場合
You can take out the record of your driving recorder
ドライブレコーダーの記録を持ち出すことができます
Can you tell someone else what you said in your driving record?
運転記録に書いてあることを他の人に伝えることができますか?
to report on someone, to report on someone, to report on someone
他人の報告、他人の報告、他人の報告
This place actually has problems
実はこの場所には問題がある
Then what I was talking about just now is that behind this
それで、今私が話したのは、この背後にあるのです
If we don't talk about the media today, we were talking about it just now.
今日メディアについて話さなければ、それについて話しただけです
We're doing something else to encourage everyone to report
私たちは皆さんに報告を促すために別の取り組みを行っています
For some traffic safety accidents, we will report
一部の交通安全事故についてご報告させていただきます。
How about a culture like this?
こんな文化はどうでしょうか？
What about everyone we meet in the future?
今後会う人はどうなるでしょうか？
Is it just
ただですか
In fact, what we need is between people
実は私たちに必要なのは人と人との間にあるのです
There is also a certain degree of mutual trust
ある程度の信頼関係もある
If the result is slow now
今結果が遅い場合
For such a mutual trust, it may take
このような相互信頼を得るには、時間がかかるかもしれません
have to reach
到達しなければならない
Is that right?
そうですか？
I think it's some problem
何か問題があると思う
really some problems
本当にいくつかの問題があります
I know it's a surveillance camera
監視カメラだということはわかっています
surveillance video recorder
監視ビデオレコーダー
the back looks like this
背面はこんな感じです
Surveillance video recorder if it goes down
監視ビデオレコーダーが停止した場合
it goes like this
こんなふうになります
Surveillance video camera current situation
監視ビデオカメラの現状
before we usually
私たちがいつもする前に
if we do anything
私たちが何かをするなら
what is usually
通常は何ですか
after what happened to you
あなたに何が起こった後
We're just starting to hold people accountable
私たちは人々に責任を負わせ始めたばかりです
let's go find
探しに行きましょう
like for example happened bro
たとえば、兄弟のように起こった
For some administrative cases
一部の行政事件については
Let's go find the criminal rights suspect
刑事権容疑者を探しに行こう
not now
今はやめろ
now our way words
今私たちのやり方の言葉
already called prevention
すでに予防と呼ばれています
we're not here to punish after the fact
私たちは事後に罰を与えるためにここにいるのではありません
but by preventing
しかし、予防することで
prevention is now
予防は今です
we are actually
私たちは実際に
imagine
想像
data to basically do anything
基本的に何でもできるデータ
In fact, it provides some preventive
実際、それはいくつかの予防策を提供します
and it's immediate
そしてそれはすぐに
then immediately
それからすぐに
and even he can tell you
そして彼でさえあなたに言うことができます
I don't just react immediately
すぐに反応するわけではない
I can prevent you again right away
すぐにまた阻止できるよ
I can tell you
教えられます
What about those places?
そういった場所はどうでしょうか？
may be crime area
犯罪地域かもしれない
who speaks for himself
自分自身を語る人
he may have some
彼はいくつか持っているかもしれない
may be guilty
有罪かもしれない
that or something
それか何か
Then this thing becomes preventive
そうすれば、これは予防になります
That's what we have now
それが今私たちが持っているものです
maybe some problems
もしかしたら何か問題があるかもしれない
so what do you want now
それで今何が欲しいですか
It's called Video on the Mac
Mac ではビデオと呼ばれます
so i took it all
だから私はそれをすべて受け取りました
Because of current technology
現在のテクノロジーのせいで
let me have this situation
この状況を許してください
I can put social
ソーシャルを入れることができます
take everything
すべてを取る
through my official
私の公式を通じて
what else
ほかに何か
Private Service Efforts
民間サービスの取り組み
official with what
何の役人
Public and private partnerships
官民パートナーシップ
I put all the information
全ての情報を載せておきます
A person's information has been collected
個人情報が収集されています
wait till it happens
それが起こるまで待ちます
I'll look for it again
また探してみます
This was what I was thinking
これが私が考えていたことでした
is ok
大丈夫です
ok then you record first
OK、それなら最初に録音してください
words after recording
録音後の言葉
if you want to use videotape
ビデオテープを使いたい場合
sorry
ごめん
you must have certain
あなたは確かなものを持っている必要があります
due process
適法手続
you can use this
これを使えます
that now now
それは今
do we do something like this
このようなことをしますか
This is
これは
possible concerns
考えられる懸念
when did you my personal information
私の個人情報をいつ知りましたか
collected by someone out of town
町外の人が集めた
Then how is he used
では彼はどのように使われるのか
announced
発表された
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
many people raised their hands
多くの人が手を挙げた
It can be seen that the reaction is very enthusiastic
反響が非常に大きいことがわかります
Hello
こんにちは
Thank you for your brilliant presentation
素晴らしいプレゼンテーションをありがとう
just ask a question
ただ質問してください
Two questions should be asked
2つの質問をする必要があります
The first question is
最初の質問は
Why do people need privacy
なぜ人はプライバシーを必要とするのか
there may be a range of answers
答えには幅があるかもしれない
Then ask the vice president about this question at the same time
それから同時にこの質問について副社長に尋ねてください
Physician
医師
I studied law with Mr. Lin
私はリン先生と一緒に法律を学びました
I personally think
個人的には思う
people need privacy
人々にはプライバシーが必要です
on the first list
最初のリストにある
The first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
Privacy Helps Creativity
プライバシーは創造性を助ける
If the individual has no privacy
個人にプライバシーがない場合
society cannot progress
社会は進歩できない
no creativity
創造性がない
Then I will ask the two teachers to accept
それから二人の先生に承諾してもらいます
The second question is to say
2番目の質問はこう言うことです
Living in a situation where all housing and transportation are under surveillance
すべての住居と交通機関が監視下にある状況での生活
everything is traceable
すべてが追跡可能です
In the past we said that the law is not subject to
以前、この法律は適用されないと言いましたが、
All can now be mailed to
すべてメールで送信できるようになりました
Essay Questions Sexuality Questions
エッセイの質問 セクシュアリティの質問
can be sent to
に送信できます
age-leading problem
加齢に伴う問題
retirement machine problem
退職金機械問題
So the whole principle of the law is broken
つまり法の原則全体が破綻している
The whole system logic system is gone
システムの論理システム全体がなくなった
That
それか
For insurance, we have to go out for oil and fill in a lot of insurance information
保険に加入するには、石油を買いに行って、たくさんの保険情報を入力しなければなりません
ID card phone
IDカード電話
Then when you see a doctor, you have to log in online
医師の診察を受けるときは、オンラインでログインする必要があります
And when there is a traffic violation, it will be registered on the Internet.
そして、交通違反をするとインターネットに登録されてしまいます。
Traffic Hear me sorry
交通 ごめんなさい聞いてください
when traffic violation
交通違反をしたとき
You can register on the Internet, you know it when you go online
インターネットで登録できます。オンラインにアクセスするとわかります
When declaring money to a certain political party or religious group
特定の政党や宗教団体に金銭を申告する場合
above all
何よりも
So as soon as these big data comes out, we will already know the result of the next election.
したがって、これらのビッグデータが出ればすぐに、次の選挙の結果が分かることになります。
We live in such an era that everyone has the opportunity to be
私たちは誰もがそうなるチャンスがある時代に生きています。
protagonist of a news scandal
ニューススキャンダルの主人公
Excuse me
すみません
just say when something like this happens
このようなことが起こったときに言ってください
how to protect yourself
自分を守る方法
Is it procedural justice?
それは手続き上の正義でしょうか？
or is there a better way
それとももっと良い方法がありますか
Thanks
ありがとう
and facebook recognition
そしてフェイスブックの認識
Can you tell if a person is homosexual?
人が同性愛者かどうかわかりますか?
Especially in the era when Qiyin is developed
特にQiyinが発展した時代には
before birth
生まれる前に
We knew this kid was a genius
私たちはこの子が天才であることを知っていました
there are still handicapped people
まだ障害者がいる
So we live in a time long gone
だから私たちは遠い昔の時代に生きている
full of challenges
課題がいっぱい
Thanks
ありがとう
You speak
あなたは話す
I speak
私は話します
I basically don't like living in a society like this
基本的にこんな社会で生きるのは嫌だ
So I was very concerned about privacy a long time ago
だから私は昔からプライバシーについてとても心配していました
district
区域
very different requirements
非常に異なる要件
very very go
とてもとても行きます
A Thousand Cups Request
千杯のリクエスト
I just want to give me a space
ただスペースを与えたいだけです
words in this space
この空間の言葉
I can be close to someone I choose
私が近くにいることを選択できる人
partner or friend
パートナーまたは友人
we can have very intimate conversations
私たちはとても親密な会話ができる
at least in that space
少なくともあの空間では
In the middle of the space, I'm still alone
宇宙の真ん中で私はまだ一人
What about the words in the middle of this space?
このスペースの真ん中にある言葉はどうでしょうか？
this my friends
これは私の友達です
he knows what i am
彼は私が何であるかを知っています
So for some existing
したがって、既存の一部については、
ups and downs they will basically
浮き沈みは基本的にあるだろう
that's how it looks
それがどのように見えるか
so you are at least alone
だからあなたは少なくとも一人です
But living in what you just described
しかし、あなたが今説明したような状況の中で生きている
this era
この時代
basically feel very
基本的にとても感じます
special
非常的
very strange
非常に奇妙な
Then everyone can watch that movie too
そうすれば、みんなもその映画を見ることができます
The Truman Show, isn't it?
トゥルーマン・ショーですね。
We like to live in the middle of that world
私たちはその世界の真ん中で生きたいと思っています
But the future is like that
でも未来ってそんなもんだよね
what shall we do
何をしましょうか
actually
実際
I should tell you one thing
何か言っておきたい
Wasn't it one of the things I talked about just now?
それは私が今話したことの一つではありませんでしたか？
That is to say, we protect the rights of photographers
つまり、写真家の権利を保護します
He actually has a saying
実は彼にはこんな名言がある
Just afraid of being wronged by others
他人から不当な扱いを受けるのが怖いだけ
understand
理解
twisted by others
他人によって歪められた
Now what you just said about DNA
DNA について今おっしゃったこと
that's been talking about one thing
それは一つのことについて話している
Human DNA is read
人間のDNAが読み取られる
then what about the enemy
じゃあ敵はどうだろう
Even after all the enemies are done
敵を全て倒しても
You get another person out again
また別の人を外に出してしまうと
Is that the original person of that person?
それはその人の本来の姿なのでしょうか？
you know this information
あなたはこの情報を知っていますか
You put together all the information on this person
この人に関する情報をすべてまとめました
is this the person
この人ですか
Probably not
おそらくそうではありません
Therefore, among our society today
したがって、今日私たちの社会の中で、
kind of missing something
何かが足りないような
In fact, we just talked about each other
実際、私たちはお互いのことについて話したばかりです
some degree of respect and trust
ある程度の敬意と信頼
is actually important
実際に重要です
When you take these basic things
こういう基本的なことを押さえると、
when everything is knocked out
すべてがノックアウトされたとき
In fact, what has become of human nature
実際、人間の本性はどうなったのか
so that privacy it exists
プライバシーが存在するように
It's about humanity
実はそれは人間性の問題なのです
Or you say that the earliest start is the instinct of animals
あるいは、一番早いスタートは動物の本能だと言うか
Animals, apart from taking each other's eggs
動物たちは、卵をお互いから取ることについて話しているだけでなく、
Others basically still have some degree of one
他の人は基本的にまだある程度の1を持っています
on a body it will have a
ボディには
I hope there is still a distance
まだ距離があることを願っています
Human basically except for that distance
その距離以外は基本的に人間
What you just said is correct
あなたが今言ったことは正しいです
Actually some things
実はいくつかのこと
very immature
とても未熟です
My privacy also protects what I am
私のプライバシーは私自身を守るものでもあります
I don't need to carry
運ぶ必要がない
That's a bit different from speech
それは話し言葉とはちょっと違います
kinda about where he is the focus
彼がどこに焦点を当てているかについて
i don't need to tell you
あなたに言う必要はありません
i have no reason to tell you
あなたに言う理由はない
because it's my privacy
それは私のプライバシーだから
That also protects me a lot
そうすれば、これも私をたくさん守ってくれます
give me plenty to think about
たくさん考えさせてください
You said you just talked about human knowledge
あなたは今人類の知識について話したと言った
Human civilization is actually related to this thing
人類の文明は実はこれに関係している
It's important that he has some protection.
彼に何らかの保護があることが重要です。
but one thing you just mentioned
でも、あなたが今言ったことが 1 つあります
actually took us to another level of discussion
実際、私たちを別のレベルの議論に連れて行ってくれました
what is human nature
人間の本性とは何ですか
What kind of society do we want to pursue?
私たちはどのような社会を目指したいのでしょうか？
words in the middle of this society
この社会の真ん中にある言葉
how each person is treated
それぞれの人がどのように扱われるか
Actually we make
実は私たちが作っているのは
In fact, the reason why this society is like this
実はこの社会がこうなっている理由
we made
私たちが作った
because we like a very safe
私たちはとても安全なものが好きなので
no society in which danger can occur
危険が起こり得る社会はない
We hope to provide very much
私たちはたくさんのことを提供したいと思っています
a service that we use very much
私たちがよく利用しているサービス
what do we want
私達は何が欲しいのか
This is what each of us wants
これが私たち一人一人が望んでいることです
and create a society like ours
私たちのような社会を作りましょう
So what you need to understand is that
したがって、理解する必要があるのは、
we demand more and more
私たちはますます尋ねます
Because of the development of technology, it is actually beyond our
テクノロジーの発展により、実際には私たちの限界を超えています。
it's beyond our imagination
それは私たちの想像を超えています
growing faster
より速く成長する
but i've always been here
でも私はいつもここにいます
Of course, we are doing some technological humanization
もちろん、私たちはテクノロジーの人間化を行っています
I was just thinking about saying that in the middle, we actually need to be more senior.
真ん中では、実際にはもっと上級者になる必要があると言おうと思っていました。
What about some things?
いくつかのことについてはどうでしょうか？
we should think about it
私たちはそれについて考えるべきです
think about it
考えてみてください
So like for example we were doing
たとえば、私たちがやっていたように
When the Human General Project
人類総合計画のとき
When the United States was doing the Human General Project
アメリカが人類総合計画を行っていた頃
then-leader Watson
当時のリーダー、ワトソン
The Watson that Norgoi talked about
ノルゴイが話したワトソン
He basically did one thing by saying
彼は基本的にこう言って一つのことをした
He asked for 3% to 5% of those doing research
研究者のうち3%から5%を求めた
Take it out and do Elsie Ethic
取り出してエルシー倫理をやってみよう
Legal and Social Impact
法的および社会的影響
a study
研究
i think he is important
彼は重要だと思います
we are now
私たちは今
Actually, we don't want to talk about this anymore.
実際のところ、これについてはもう話したくないのです。
Let's talk about AI first
まずはAIについて話しましょう
AI development
AI開発
You immediately see the development of AI
AIの発展がすぐにわかります
amazing, isn't it
すごいですね
The AI ​​is also pretty amazing
AIもかなりすごいですね
What if his development continues
彼の成長が続いたらどうなるか
words at this time
この時の言葉
This is what we keep saying we can control
これは私たちがコントロールできると言い続けていることです
is that true
本当
I think this is what we all have in common
これが私たち全員の共通点だと思います
common mission
共通の使命
honestly no solution
正直解決策はない
We give young people a chance to speak
私たちは若者に発言の機会を与えます
Gai, are you starting?
ガイ、始めますか？
good
良い
that
それか
Hello President Lin
こんにちは、林社長
Then what I also want to ask is
それから、私も聞きたいのは、
Because of the recent EU
最近のEUのせいで
It should have been last year or the year before the EU
去年かEU加盟前の前年だったはず
through a so-called right of memorandum judgment
いわゆる覚書判決の権利を通じて
The true meaning of this judgment
この判決の本当の意味
I think the main thing is to say
肝心なことはこう言うことだと思います
When personal film and television rights and freedom of speech rights
個人の映画やテレビの権利と言論の自由の権利の場合
when a collision occurs
衝突が起こったとき
the court of the European Union
欧州連合の裁判所
He chose to use his personal film and television rights
彼は個人的な映画とテレビの権利を使用することを選択しました
there is a more important part
もっと重要な部分があります
so he said
それで彼は言いました
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
He said that with personal film and television rights
彼は、個人的な映画とテレビの権利を持っていると言いました
there is a more important part
もっと重要な部分があります
i want to ask
聞きたいです
that
それか
The professor's or director's view on this matter
この件に関する教授またはディレクターの見解
right
右
Thanks
ありがとう
In fact, there is still a lot of research that can be done.
実際、できる研究はまだたくさんあります。
But basically it's like this
でも基本的にはこんな感じです
I'll start with a basic response that says
という基本的な応答から始めます。
He wants to become concrete and feasible
彼は具体的で実現可能になりたいと考えています
yes still need to spend
はい、まだ使う必要があります
He actually has to be a little more detailed
実際にはもう少し詳しく説明する必要があります
Of course you know the right to be forgotten
もちろんあなたは忘れられる権利を知っています
if the experiment
実験なら
What price do we pay for this
これに我々はいくらの代償を払うのか
When the judgment was first
最初の判決のとき
some people just say
ただ言う人もいます
Well, the history of mankind will
さて、人類の歴史は、
there will be no history
歴史はなくなる
because everyone can
誰もができるから
forgotten
忘れられた
The history of mankind is basically
人類の歴史は基本的には
everyone's behavior
みんなの行動
He said
彼は言った
this constructed
これは構築された
As a result, each piece was removed
その結果、各部分が削除されました
Take this piece off this piece
この部分をこの部分から外してください
so you can see the right to be forgotten
そうすれば忘れられる権利があることがわかります
There must be many exceptions behind him
彼の背後には多くの例外があるに違いない
he must have many exceptions
彼には多くの例外があるに違いない
including what you just mentioned
今言ったことも含めて
free speech part
自由言論部分
he will have an exception
彼には例外があるだろう
but where is that specific thing
しかし、その具体的なものはどこにありますか
this stuff needs to be talked about
このことについては話し合う必要がある
Then from my legal point of view
それから、私の法的な観点から言えば、
when you come to see this
これを見に来たら
I think there is an American scholar
アメリカの学者がいると思います
he speaks very well
彼はとても上手に話します
He said we really need
彼は私たちが本当に必要だと言いました
not the right to be forgotten
忘れられる権利ではない
but should be
しかしそうあるべきです
the right to be forgiven
許される権利
not forget but forgiven
忘れるのではなく許してください
everyone should know
誰もが知っておくべきです
you and i can both make mistakes
あなたも私も間違いを犯す可能性があります
Everyone should have second chance
誰もが二度目のチャンスを持つべきだ
Will we hold on to this one
これを我慢しましょうか
You and I have empathy over there
あなたと私はそこに共感を持っています
Then look at such a thing
じゃあそんなものを見てみろよ
that might
その可能性があります
would maybe
たぶん
we are not sure
私たちにはわかりません
But what he said about the right to be forgotten
しかし、忘れられる権利について彼はこう言った
Behind him is actually everyone else
彼の後ろには実は他の全員がいる
you can watch
あなたは見ることができます
because you can watch another thing
別のものが見れるから
is behind some
いくつかの後ろにあります
political economy issues
政治経済問題
This is what the EU ruled
これはEUが決めたことだ
Canada then
そのときカナダ
that's american
それはアメリカ人です
company
会社
behind him he has many other
彼の後ろには他にもたくさんいる
can be discussed
議論できる
But he is a very important question
しかし、彼は非常に重要な質問です
he is a very problem
彼はとても問題がある
Me you wish I had a yes no or something
私に「はい、いいえ」か何かがあればよかったのに
The gentleman in the back, he goes to the back
後ろの紳士、彼は後ろに行きます
Hello Professor Lin
こんにちは、リン先生
Well, actually, thank you very much for your wonderful speech just now.
そうですね、今は素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。
right from your speech
あなたのスピーチからすぐに
You will know that in fact the development of technology
実際にテクノロジーの発展によって
Including AI, including IoT, including BDIR
AIを含む、IoTを含む、BDIRを含む
These actually come from all over the world
これらは実際には世界中から来ています
Here, if you look at both sides
ここで両面を見てみると
On the one hand, this force of privacy infringement
一方で、このプライバシー侵害の力は、
It's like what I just said
それは私が今言ったことのようです
we wish good luck
私たちは幸運を祈ります
But that is actually the current technology
でもそれが実は現在の技術なのです
This is the strength of our Protect Private side
これが私たちのプライベートを守る側の強みです
Obviously asymmetrical
明らかに非対称
or this part of our effort
または私たちの取り組みのこの部分
Asymmetrical on both sides
両側非対称
Here is actually already
ここは実はもうすでに
I don't know what will happen in the future
将来何が起こるか分かりません
invasion of privacy
プライバシー侵害
So sometimes I think a lot
だから時々すごく考えるんです
then more helpless
そうなるとさらに無力になる
Then the more afraid
そうすればもっと怖くなる
the one who just mentioned to you
先ほどあなたに話した人
There are many of these in our country
私たちの国にはこうしたものがたくさんあります
This Ethical or this Effort of Private C
この倫理、あるいは民間Cのこの取り組み
Maybe a few Percent or not even a few Percent
おそらく数パーセント、あるいは数パーセントではないかもしれません
Effort is not big enough so I don't know how to say this two
努力が足りないので、この2つをどう言えばいいのかわかりません
Several levels and one level means from the perspective of the country
複数のレベルと1つのレベルは、国から見た意味です
In addition, from the perspective of dealing with these large enterprises
また、こうした大企業への対応という観点からも、
And what do we personally want from Sebastian's perspective?
そして、セバスチャンの観点から私たちは個人的に何を望んでいますか？
Maybe it means that the situation develops like this
おそらく状況がこのように発展することを意味します
Sometimes the more you understand, the more helpless you will be
理解すればするほど無力になることがある
It's happening so I don't know what we should do
それが起こっているので、私たちは何をすべきかわかりません
Look at this matter with a more positive attitude
もっと前向きな姿勢でこの問題を見てください
thanks for this difficult question
難しい質問をありがとう
There is another saying that goes like this
他にもこんな諺があります
Everyone is a real villain
みんな本当の悪役だよ
It means that I have something to hide
つまり、隠したいことがあるということです
I am like this, but you are also like this
私はこうだけどあなたもこうだ
The Song and Ming Dynasties just mentioned
先ほど触れた宋と明の時代
That is our predecessor Wang Fuyuan
それが私たちの先代の王福源です。
At that time, I asked him about film and television rights.
その時、私は彼に映画とテレビの権利について尋ねました。
He told me a few things
彼は私にいくつかのことを言いました
be the first to talk about this
このことについて最初に話してみませんか
He said that the husband of the Song Dynasty
彼は宋王朝の夫だと言った。
Basically think that there is nothing to hide
基本的に隠すことは何もないと考えています
other than that
それ以外
He also told me about the May 4th Movement
彼は五・四運動についても話してくれました。
the words of these workers
この労働者たちの言葉
Just like Hu's leaders
胡氏らのような指導者と同じように
Basically they are exchanging diaries
基本的には交換日記です
The exchange of diaries is to let you know
交換日記はあなたに知らせることです
what am i doing what are you doing
私は何をしているのですか、あなたは何をしていますか
Everyone has one like that
誰でもそういう人はいるよ
A case of interior
インテリアの一例
Well, on the other hand?
さて、一方では？
I found that when he was talking to me about this
彼がこのことについて私に話していたときに気づきました
I just wanted to say oops
おっと言いたかっただけです
At that time my daughter was in primary school
当時娘は小学生でした
They also exchange diaries
交換日記もある
Then you can see today
そしたら今日も見れるよ
I don't use Facebook yet
Facebookはまだ使っていません
But all my friends around me are using Facebook
でも周りの友達はみんなFacebookを使っている
All my friends are on facebook
私の友達はみんなフェイスブックを使っています
Under such circumstances
このような状況下では
you'll think it's ok
あなたは大丈夫だと思うでしょう
Is it a change of mind?
心変わりですか？
Because we may the environment in which we grow
なぜなら、私たちは成長する環境を変えることができるからです。
because we grew up in that
私たちはその中で育ったから
The era of authoritarian regimes
独裁政権の時代
So for our individual
それで、私たちの個人的なこととしては、
personal privacy
個人のプライバシー
is very caring
とても思いやりがあります
but us
でも私たち
I'm like Pew my daughter
私はピューの娘のようです
words of their generation
彼らの世代の言葉
they live in a happy
彼らは幸せに暮らしています
Looks like a happy time
幸せな時間のようですね
So basically speaking
基本的に言えば
like
好き
nothing
なし
Then on the other hand
それから一方では
Is it real
本当ですか
Notions of privacy change
プライバシーの概念が変化する
I used to think I didn't want to give you
あげたくないと思ってた
The current concept has become called Sharing
現在の概念は「共有」と呼ばれるようになりました
like this one on facebook
フェイスブックでこれにいいね！
the founder
創設者
Zuber was in 2002
ズーバーは2002年に
Note that it is 2002
2002年であることに注意してください
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
actually
実際
I just mentioned that because
私はちょうどそれを言ったので、
Behind Privacy, he is actually related to Social Know
プライバシーの背後にある彼は、実際にはソーシャル ノウに関係しています
He said that the current Social Know has changed
現在のソーシャルノウは変わったと彼は言いました
So what?
だから何？
Don't talk to me about Privacy anymore
もうプライバシーについて私に話さないでください
Because now Social Know has changed
今はソーシャルノウが変わったから
so stop talking about this
だからこのことについて話すのはやめてください
As a result he was in 2002
その結果、彼は2002年に
he was pushing
彼は押していた
That Facebook is pushing a new Privacy Policy
Facebook が新しいプライバシー ポリシーを推進していること
The result is immediately
結果はすぐに
slap in the face
顔を平手打ちする
Immediately changed again
すぐにまた変わりました
But what he said later was actually
しかし、後で彼が言ったのは実際には
is worth saying
言う価値がある
Is it true that Social norms have changed
社会規範が変わったというのは本当ですか
What we cared about in the past is what we care about now
私たちが過去に大切にしていたものは、今私たちが大切にしているものです
its new generation it may
その新世代はそうかもしれない
it feels nothing
何も感じない
It feels like nothing needs to be like this
何もこうである必要はないような気がする
But in the end, of course, there is a question of
しかし、最終的には、もちろん問題があります。
no matter how you look
どう見えても
can have so many friends
たくさんの友達ができる
and then there are so many
そして、とてもたくさんあります
So much information that can be exchanged with friends
友達と交換できる情報がたくさん
then the last words
それから最後の言葉
do you keep a little bit
少しだけ取っておきますか
I don't want others to know
他人に知られたくない
I'm quite curious
とても興味があります
We also need to pass
私たちも合格する必要があります
Maybe big data
たぶんビッグデータ
should be through the fact
事実を通してあるべきだ
Some empirical research should be done
いくつかの実証研究を行う必要がある
Really do some empirical research
本当に実証研究をしてください
what can we dare say
あえて何を言うことができますか
Then what we just talked about are some
それでは、私たちが今話した内容の一部をご紹介します
Relatively general
比較一般
Everyone seems to think it's something like this
みんなこんな感じだと思うよ
a concept
一種觀念
So has a concept changed?
それでコンセプトが変わったのでしょうか？
On the other hand, of course
その一方で、もちろん
there is another possibility
別の可能性があります
i've been thinking about this
私はこれについて考えてきました
That means you like, say, Facebook
それは、たとえば Facebook が好きということです
you are so old
あなたはとても年をとりました
it is already transnational
それはすでに国境を越えています
what else can you do
他に何ができますか
Of course one thing we want to do is say
もちろん、私たちが言いたいことの 1 つは、
We have seen them in order to compete
私たちは競争するために彼らを見てきました
So their words they will take this seriously
だから彼らの言葉を彼らは真剣に受け止めるだろう
User consumer
ユーザー消費者
So find a way to keep the market open to competition
したがって、市場を競争に開かれた状態に保つ方法を見つけてください
Basically, the other side of technology we see is
基本的に、私たちが見ているテクノロジーの裏側は次のとおりです。
He is soon to be as big as he is today
彼はもうすぐ今日と同じくらい大きくなるだろう
He will be gone tomorrow, right?
彼は明日いなくなるんですよね？
he is like this sometimes
彼は時々こんな感じです
But what we're more worried about is where the information goes.
しかし、私たちがもっと心配しているのは、情報がどこへ行くのかということです。
It's not the problem that you didn't introduce that information.
あなたがその情報を紹介しなかったことが問題なのではありません。
but that information
しかしその情報は
That information may be like this, he has always existed, right?
その情報はこうかもしれません、彼はずっと存在していましたよね？
That's what we just mentioned
それが今お話ししたことです
That question of Right to be, to forget, forgotten
存在する権利、忘れる権利、忘れられる権利の問題
The words in that place are information
そこにある言葉は情報だ
because at any time and forever he always exists
なぜなら、いつでも永遠に彼は常に存在するからです
We hope he doesn't exist, don't act like this
彼が存在しないことを願っています、このような行為をしないでください
Then we have to think about it now
それなら今考えなければなりません
very practical question
非常に実践的な質問
What kind of time did these things happen?
これらのことはどのような時に起こったのでしょうか？
don't be so scared
そんなに怖がらないでください
You don't have to be so fearful
そんなに恐れる必要はないよ
Then I'll be melancholy over there every day
そうしたら毎日あそこで憂鬱になるよ
what happened
どうしたの
That's what we have to know after
それは私たちがその後に知らなければならないことです
we can find a solution
私たちは解決策を見つけることができます
But the problem is we don't know what's going on right now
しかし問題は、今何が起こっているのか分からないことです
that's the trouble
それが問題だ
So what I said just now is to say
つまり、今私が言ったことは、
Everyone worked hard to find a way to get him out
誰もが彼を追い出す方法を見つけるために一生懸命働きました
Because of this time constraint
この時間的制約があるため、
I want to ask a few people to answer together
数人にまとめて答えてもらいたいです
Then you stay until 12 o'clock in the evening
それから夜の12時まで滞在します
The rest is to discuss with him
残りは彼と話し合うことです
You can go up front and discuss with him
あなたは前に出て彼と話し合うことができます
Just this one, these three, okay?
この 1 つ、この 3 つだけでいいですか?
You all asked together and you answered together
皆さんは一緒に質問し、一緒に答えました
Wait a minute, you can ask the second person and the third person
ちょっと待って、2人目と3人目に聞いてもいいよ
Sorry, that teacher just mentioned that
申し訳ありませんが、その先生はちょうどそれについて言いました
This is the age of the Internet of Things
今はモノのインターネットの時代です
Because of the Internet of Things era
モノのインターネット時代のせいで
we know he collects
私たちは彼が集めていることを知っています
The information is quite comprehensive
情報は非常に包括的です
But look at this in our country
しかし、私たちの国でこれを見てください
personal protection law
個人保護法
he actually still
彼は実際にはまだ
Is it possible to identify individuals
個人を特定することは可能ですか
Then fine no longer go to authorize the competent authority
そうすれば罰金は管轄当局の認可に行かなくなります
Do some enumerated behaviors to determine whether it is an asset
いくつかの列挙された動作を実行して、それが資産であるかどうかを判断します
But in the era when the teacher just mentioned the Internet of Things
しかし、先ほど先生がモノのインターネットについて言及した時代には
With the data you collected so comprehensive,
収集した非常に包括的なデータにより、
data set
データセット
Use it to de-identify a person
個人を匿名化するために使用する
Then I was thinking about this part. I don’t know if I can ask the teacher for advice.
それで、この部分について考えたのですが、先生にアドバイスを求めてもいいのかわかりません。
Is there a more suitable way
もっと適切な方法はありますか
To confirm what level of information is considered a qualification
どのレベルの情報が資産とみなされているかを確認するため
Or make it a more
あるいはそれ以上にする
It is more in line with a definition like this used in practice
これは、実際に使用されているこのような定義とより一致しています。
Ask the teacher this question, thank you
先生にこの質問をしてください、ありがとう
Hello Professor Lin
こんにちは、リン先生
I want to go along with the concept of privacy you just said
今おっしゃったプライバシーの考え方に沿っていきたいと思います
Let's talk about this place
この場所について話しましょう
Because I listened to tonight's lecture and felt
今夜の講演を聞いて感じたから
Your right to privacy in the context of the current information society
現在の情報社会におけるプライバシーの権利
There is a deep worry about being violated
侵害されるのではないかという強い不安がある
There is also a pessimistic mood
悲観的な雰囲気もある
what about me
私はどうなの
Think about it from another perspective
別の視点から考えてみましょう
because
なぜなら
I think maybe the concept of privacy may indeed undergo some changes under the background of this information
おそらくプライバシーの概念は、この情報を背景に実際に何らかの変化を起こす可能性があると思います
Then I would like to propose the concepts of absolute privacy, relative privacy and bottom-line privacy
次に、絶対的なプライバシー、相対的なプライバシー、そして最終的なプライバシーという概念を提案したいと思います。
because the bottom line is
なぜなら、肝心なのは
because
なぜなら
I think in this context of information
この情報の文脈で私は思う
we enjoyed the message
私たちはメッセージを楽しみました
as a resource or a
リソースとして、または
a convenience of exchange
交換の利便性
We don't just see a privacy violation
プライバシー侵害だけではありません
harm to person or personality
人や人格に危害を与える
at the same time
同時に
have some rights
何らかの権利がある
There are some private rights before the public interest
公益以前に私権がいくつかある
Is it necessary to release
リリースする必要がありますか
just for personal sake
ただ個人的な目的のため
in the public interest or for the benefit of others
公共の利益または他人の利益のために
He may want to release some of his personal space and private information
彼は自分の個人的なスペースや個人情報の一部を公開したいと考えているかもしれません
For example, as a public figure or political figure
たとえば、公人や政治家として
we have a right to know about him
私たちには彼のことを知る権利があります
In addition, how should the so-called reporting and supervision rights be divided?
また、いわゆる報告権と監督権はどのように分けるべきでしょうか。
Yeah, I thought maybe those powers needed to be protected.
そうですね、おそらくそれらの力は保護される必要があると思いました。
It's just that when balancing the various powers
ただ、さまざまな力のバランスをとるとき、
When the law is established
法律が制定されると
how to set a rule or boundary
ルールや境界線を設定する方法
This may be something we need to think about
これは私たちが考えなければならないことかもしれません
you are studying law
あなたは法律を勉強しています
Yes, Thanks
はい、ありがとう
and that little girl
そしてあの小さな女の子
hello professor
こんにちは教授
what i want to ask is
私が聞きたいのは
just during the speech
ちょうどスピーチの最中に
You will hear that the development of science and technology
テクノロジーの発展って聞きますよね
is that they actually depend on some of the privacy that we the people provide
それは、彼らが実際に私たち国民が提供するプライバシーの一部に依存しているということです
It feels like our right to privacy has nothing to do with the development of modern technology
プライバシーに対する私たちの権利は、現代のテクノロジーの発展とは何の関係もないように感じます
is a bit like interdependence
相互依存に少し似ています
Then there is also the concept of interlocking
それから連動という概念もあります
Then what I want to ask is
そこで聞きたいのは、
just in technological progress
まさに技術進歩の途中
That moment when we still need our privacy
まだプライバシーが必要な瞬間
It just feels a little bit about our power
私たちの力について少しだけ感じます
There is a feeling of conflict
葛藤の感情がある
Then what I want to ask is this kind of public welfare part
それで、私が聞きたいのは、こういう公共の福祉の部分なんです。
It is a technological advancement
それは技術の進歩です
with human rights
人権とともに
between our own privacy
私たち自身のプライバシーの間で
That's how to measure the legitimacy
それが正当性を測る方法です
yes thank you
はい、ありがとうございます
I just came back to say
言いに帰ってきただけです
i'm not totally pessimistic
私は完全に悲観的ではありません
I just meant to mention
ただ言いたかっただけです
A free flow of information is very important
情報の自由な流れは非常に重要です
the free flow of information
情報の自由な流れ
Of course including his free collection
もちろん彼の無料コレクションも含めて
So I will answer from the back first
それでは、まず後ろからお答えします
that is
あれは
In this part I just mentioned a suggestion
この部分では、提案について述べました。
in fact it is
実際それは
make it public for debate
議論のために公開する
in the final analysis
最終的な分析では
what about today
今日はどうですか
These data relate to personal data
これらのデータは個人データに関連します
Or related to personal film and television materials
または個人的な映画やテレビの素材に関連するもの
why is it so important
なぜそんなに重要なのでしょうか
Need to become technology development
技術開発になる必要がある
or a necessity for its development
またはその開発に必要なもの
let everyone understand
みんなに理解してもらいましょう
If so
もしそうなら
Maybe we can make a comparison
もしかしたら比較できるかもしれない
We all know the situation and do something very understanding
私たちは皆状況を知っており、よく理解されたことを行っています
Now we don't know
今は分かりません
is a possibly abstract statement
抽象的なステートメントである可能性があります
Of course we understand that
もちろんそれは理解しています
the more the merrier
多いほどもっと良いでしょう
how much is that
いくらですか
to what extent
どの程度まで
I just started talking
話し始めたばかりです
I just need to identify
ただ識別する必要がある
Then start to get a little bit out of touch with the individual
それから、その人と少し距離を置き始めます。
you use that data
あなたはそのデータを使用します
but sometimes
でも時々
it needs that identifying information
その識別情報が必要です
So this middle word
したがって、この中間の単語は
Trade-offs are up for debate
トレードオフは議論の余地がある
i think it should be
そうあるべきだと思う
After IoT comes out, basically
IoTが出てきてからは基本的には
In fact, the current difficulty is like this
実は現在の難易度はこんな感じ
That is to say, I feel that the Personal Data Protection Act
つまり、個人情報保護法は、
It has to face a new problem which is to say
それは新たな問題に直面しなければなりません。
you thought you meant
あなたはそれが意味していると思いました
identify
識別
that thing that is identifiable enough
十分に識別可能なもの
The so-called teaching profile
いわゆる指導プロフィール
Now if we look at it with our current technology
今の技術で考えてみると
Almost every piece of information is sufficient to identify
ほぼすべての情報で特定できます
Insufficient recognition today becomes sufficient recognition tomorrow
今日の不十分な認識は明日には十分な認識になる
So how do you face such a problem?
では、そのような問題にどうやって対処しますか?
I think our current personal data protection law
現在の個人情報保護法は
his words in many places
多くの場所での彼の言葉
He hasn't put a question like this
彼はこのような質問をしていません
He brought into his normative thinking
彼は規範的思考を持ち込んだ
So I think he's thinking about this part of the question
つまり、彼は質問のこの部分について考えているのだと思います
It should be like what I just mentioned
先ほど述べたようなものになるはずです
should be opened
開かれるべきです
Let's discuss and debate
議論して議論しましょう
What should be like is a reasonable
あるべき姿は合理的である
As I said just now, it is not one-sided
先ほども言いましたが、一方的なものではありません
he should be a balanced
彼はバランスが取れているはずだ
We want to give people a certain degree of space
私たちは人々にある程度のスペースを与えたいと考えています
as mentioned earlier
前述したように
may be an underlying
根底にあるかもしれない
look at the words you use, sorry
あなたが使う言葉を見てごめんなさい
The word you use is the bottom line is the bottom line
あなたが使う言葉が最終的なものです
That's what I don't exchange with you
それは私があなたと交換しないことです
Other words depend on your personal status
他の言葉はあなたの個人的なステータスに依存します
or comtest
またはコンテスト
maybe he's somehow
たぶん彼はどういうわけか
is required may be can be collected
必要です 収集できる場合があります
can be revealed
明らかにすることができます
so it is true
それは本当です
So to resist the contest
だからコンテストに抵抗するために
I think it is to resist the contest
競争に抵抗するためだと思う
That's basically true in Taiwan
台湾では基本的にそうだよ
some people basically
基本的に一部の人は
He enjoys less
彼はあまり楽しんでいない
some people have more
もっと持っている人もいます
But of course this is not the case now
しかし、もちろん今はそうではありません
What we are talking about today is his general
今日私たちが話しているのは彼の将軍についてです
He basically wants more information
彼は基本的により多くの情報を望んでいます
more information
詳しくは
is better
優れている
Because I'm not an expert on this
私はこの件については専門家ではないので、
so i thought it meant
だからそれが意味すると思った
need to talk
話す必要がある
And then this dialogue
そして、この対話
comparative intellectual circles
比較知的サークル
probably general public
おそらく一般人
let's get to know
知りましょう
because we talk a lot about
私たちはよく話すから
The final decision is yours
最終的な決断はあなた次第です
may affect everyone
全員に影響を与える可能性があります
so he needs to be like this
だから彼はこうである必要がある
I think I'm not that pessimistic
そこまで悲観的ではないと思う
i just feel like saying
ただ言いたい気分です
If this kind of development continues
このような展開が続けば
at least we need to know
少なくとも私たちは知る必要があります
This is after I made a choice
これは私が選択した後です
I made a choice
私は選択をしました
if there is no answer
答えがない場合
Those three come back later
あの三人はまた後で来ます
let's go on
続けましょう
I think because the time has come
時期が来たからだと思う
Then I think before officially announcing the end
それから正式に終了を発表する前に考えます
I have one more thing to announce
もう一つ発表したいことがあります
this is the trailer
これはトレーラーです
this is a teaser
これはティーザーです
First on October 17th in October 106
最初は10月106日の10月17日
Center for Academic Activities at Southport at the Midshore Institute
ミッドショア研究所サウスポート学術活動センター
The first meeting on the second floor of the Zhonghe Research Institute is
中和研究所２階での初会合は、
The same feast of knowledge
同じ知識の饗宴
We have an Earth Science Institute
私たちには地球科学研究所があります
Researcher Xu Yaru
研究者シュ・ヤル
The lecture will be based on the Great Earthquake of the Last Era
先代の大震災を題材に講義を行います
take the tsunami
津波を受け止めて
Frequent earthquakes recently
最近地震が多い
So you may also be interested in this topic
あなたもこのトピックに興味があるかもしれません
Well I think we see you today
それでは今日はみんなに会えると思います
Interacting with this teacher Lin so enthusiastically
リン先生とのやりとりがとても熱心
Then said that this speech resonated a lot
そして、このスピーチはとても反響があったと言いました
i think wait there may be a little time
少し時間があるかもしれないので待ってください
Let everyone who is intrepid can ask him for advice
勇敢な人は誰でも彼にアドバイスを求めましょう
Then let's applaud now and thank Team Leader Lin
それでは拍手を送り、チームリーダーのリンに感謝しましょう
thank you thank you thank you
ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう
thank you all thank you
みんなありがとう、ありがとう